<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
	<updated>2016-12-01T17:25:18-05:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Will Hanley</name>
			
			
				<email>whanley@fsu.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://nationality-history.info/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.2">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/rymer-technical/</id>
			<title>Technical</title>
			<link href="/technical/rymer-technical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical" />
			<updated>2016-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>CharlieRymer</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>New technology always leads to technical issues, it&#39;s important to know their causes.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/rymer-technical/">&lt;p&gt;A large portion of this class involves using completely new technologies and applying them to very difficult media.  While technologies such as github, OCR, and
XML weren’t terribly hard to learn, the application of them for the first time definitely led me to some technical errors that had to be sorted out.  These technical errors
included poor text recognition that left much of the text unusable, difficult to obtain XML software, and incorrect XML tagging.  The first of these errors can be attributed
to poor condition of century old documents.  While I was able to focus the microfilm reader very well, many portions of these documents had text that was copied slightly on
top of itself and occasionally with weak ink.  This led to problems such as columns being mixed together, text that didn’t go through OCR at all, and many errors overall.
Another technical error I faced was incorrect XML tagging.  After I made all the divs in a page cascade perfectly, I found out that I had tagged headers and subheaders using
the wrong tags, which was solved using find and replace and also a lot of rearranging of the XML.  Overall, I was able to understand these new technologies fairly smoothly,
and I was able to determine the cause of a few technical errors that came up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical" />
			
			

			<published>2016-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/</id>
			<title>Discussion of Converting Text</title>
			<link href="/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discussion of Converting Text" />
			<updated>2016-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>ChristianRagland&lt;!--- all one word ---&gt;</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>My version of venting about my woes within this class.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/">&lt;p&gt;My biggest problem with the entire process has been with the OCR process. Perhaps due to poor original scans, or perhaps due to poor images
from the source, I have had serious problems with my OCR coming out correctly. Unfortunately, I’ve had to manually type every page and it has
caused me countless headaches and more than one mental breakdown. Luckily, things got a bit smoother after finishing all my page 3’s. That being
said, I’m still working extremely hard at catching up and finishing what I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical" />
			
			
				<category term="Scan" />
			
				<category term="OCR" />
			

			<published>2016-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20questions/Sain-Serial-Discovery/</id>
			<title>Dead Doggies</title>
			<link href="/serial%20questions/Sain-Serial-Discovery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dead Doggies" />
			<updated>2016-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>hannahsain</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Dogs Found and Poisoned by Police if Unclaimed</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20questions/Sain-Serial-Discovery/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;dogs-sentenced-to-death&quot;&gt;Dogs Sentenced to Death&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some of the issues, under the “Local and General” section of the paper, there are sometimes small articles labeled “Stray and Ownerless Dogs,” which is a report of the dogs that have been found that day and where there were discovered. The snippets also always say that the dogs are to be poisoned if not collected. I find this section of the newspaper interesting because it is the announcement of very miniscule news. I find the local and general portion important because it shows the minor details that occur in the day-to-day lives of the citizens of Alexandria. It’s interesting to compare the way animals are talked about in 1905 as compared to now. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.americanhumane.org/about-us/history/&quot;&gt;In 1905 animals&lt;/a&gt; were viewed mostly as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=kn9xAAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA214&amp;amp;lpg=PA214&amp;amp;dq=treatment+of+animals+in+1905&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=bOPeHYezYT&amp;amp;sig=Ew1RbTvDBxKcu8IgZF0b9YwgfZ4&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi8v7TIl8rQAhUBEGMKHc73A4gQ6AEIJzAC#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=treatment%20of%20animals%20in%201905&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;agricultural resource&lt;/a&gt; rather than house pets, like how we use them now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/two-dog-pic.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Two Dogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs were not valued as greatly as they are now. In 1905, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=2189AQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA609&amp;amp;lpg=PA609&amp;amp;dq=why+were+dogs+poisoned+by+police+1905&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=f2oUZReMBt&amp;amp;sig=zgJ_Y7hHagKLWJyaSBzxSvfPVZA&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiDvPzgmcrQAhVCqFQKHQQJAQ8Q6AEINDAE#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=poisoned%20dogs&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;the poisoning (and drowning)&lt;/a&gt; of dogs was common and is expected to happen if dogs are found stray and are not claimed. This section may be useful because people could potentially have their animals returned to them, although the declaration of their poisoning is slightly depressing, it is fascinating that it is mentioned in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/picasso-dog.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Picasso Dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial questions" />
			
			
				<category term="Animals" />
			
				<category term="Police" />
			
				<category term="Poison" />
			
				<category term="Pets" />
			

			<published>2016-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/grieco-technical/</id>
			<title>OCR Woes</title>
			<link href="/technical/grieco-technical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR Woes" />
			<updated>2016-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>dantegrieco</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>OCR: A Tale of Misery, Loss, and Misfortune</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/grieco-technical/">&lt;p&gt;For my technical reflection, I have decided to discuss my experiences with the
OCR software, simply because it was easily the most time-consuming and tedious
portion of the technical aspects of this class. Since I have a Mac laptop, I
used the Cisdem OCR software rather than ABBY Finereader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I would like to say is the accuracy with which it translates
the text is quite disappointing. I would estimate that at MOST 60% of the
original text was transcribed to my text editor properly, and even more
frustrating was that specific letters were nearly almost incorrectly written,
for instance the letter “e” for the entirety of the respective pages was often
incorrectly recorded as the letter “a”, and vice versa. Furthermore,
spell-checking entire pages written in French was both lengthy and difficult,
particularly when I could not read some of the words and could not use context
clues to figure out what they were supposed to say (because I do not speak
French). At a certain point I had to simply accept that my XML pages were simply
going to be filled with egregious errors and a certain level of accuracy was
impossible to achieve (much to the chagrin of my mild OCD, but hey it was a
learning experience in patience and Zen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was not a fan of the OCR software. It was most likely faster than
manually transcribing entire pages of the newspaper, but it was nonetheless
aggravating and stressful. Rant over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical" />
			
			
				<category term="OCR" />
			
				<category term="Cisdem PDFConverterOCR" />
			
				<category term="Mac text editor" />
			

			<published>2016-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/crawford-worldsworstjob/</id>
			<title>The World&#39;s Worst Job</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/crawford-worldsworstjob/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The World&#39;s Worst Job" />
			<updated>2016-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>williamcrawford</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary></summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/crawford-worldsworstjob/">&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through the financial tables listed on January 9th, I came across a chart detailing ivory deliveries to London. In the midst of reflecting on what 39 tons of elephant tusks would look like, I noticed an odd source of ivory mentioned in the chart: “Sea Horse Teeth.” This piqued my curiosity, as I had no idea that sea horses were a source of ivory. I immediately began to scheme–I could open the first sustainable sea horse ivory farm.  But in the midst of this, a problem arose. How does one extract sea horse teeth? Tweezers and a magnifying glass? That sounds like a painstakingly miserable job. Also the chart mentioned that 10 cwt. 1 qrs. 14 lb. (about 144 pounds) of sea horse teeth were delivered! How long would extracting that many teeth take? It might be a venture perfectly suited for the British Colonial project, but I realized I had much less capital to work with (also less forced native labor). It dawned on me that there is no earthly way that this chart is talking about the same sea horse that I am familiar with. A google search revealed I was not the first person to be puzzled about the true source of this ivory. &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldblockwriter.blogspot.com/2013/01/the-mystery-of-seahorse-teeth.html&quot;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; describes a writer’s journey though old trade documents to discover what animal exactly is being referred to after encountering a similar reference to sea horse teeth, before finally realizing that sea horses don’t even have teeth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/seahorsedentist.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;seahorsedentist.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Misinformed Propaganda&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His conclusion was that it depended on the source of the shipment. If from the polar areas, it would be walrus, but if from Africa, it would be referring to hippopotamus teeth. I admit, in this context hippopotamus teeth makes a lot more sense. The word hippopotamus originally comes from Greek, and translates to “river horse,” while the genus of the seahorse, hippocampus, comes from the Greek words for horse and sea monster. It would seem perhaps that these animals were named a bit backwards. I haven’t been able to find official data on seahorse attack fatalities, but what I have read of hippopotamus’ make them seem far more monstrous, with one article quoting a statistic provided by the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates foundation that the animal causes upwards of 500 fatalities a year. This chart also provides a snapshot of the global ivory trade before it was realized how much environmental damage was actually being done. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://nationalgeographic.org/media/history-ivory-trade/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; for a short documentary on the subject. So while my hopes for a sustainable ivory business might be dashed, I suppose the sea horses can rest easy for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="trade" />
			
				<category term="environment" />
			
				<category term="wild life" />
			
				<category term="ivory" />
			

			<published>2016-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial/Events-in-Alexandria/</id>
			<title>Events in Alexandria</title>
			<link href="/serial/Events-in-Alexandria/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Events in Alexandria" />
			<updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>SamanthaLappin</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A look into the frequency of public events in the Alexandria and Cairo calendars</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial/Events-in-Alexandria/">&lt;p&gt;One of the most important aspects of culture is the method in which people who share this culture are united. This method of uniting people can be either through language, like in Germany where the dialects are of the utmost importance, or through sports like the Mayan civilizations. I intend to determine the most common public event in Alexandria, in an attempt to gain insight into that which united the people of Alexandria, Egypt even though they were of varying social class and nationality. I plan on discovering the most common public event in the area by collecting information from all of the calendars in the paper and making a full calendar of events for 1905. From there, I’m going to analyze the proportions of events listed and the type of events. From there, I’ll be able to determine the most popular public event in Alexandria, assuming that events that occur more often would be so because they are popular among the people. If the event occurs often, insinuating it’s popular among the people, then it must be at least part of what brings the people together. Thus, while the answer to “what united the people of Alexandria” may be much harder to answer than that which can be found via a simple search of one year of a newspaper, simply determining which events occurred most often could provide a useful beginning to developing the whole of the answer to that much larger question.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial" />
			
			
				<category term="calendar" />
			
				<category term="events" />
			
				<category term="races" />
			

			<published>2016-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial/hofmeister-changes/</id>
			<title>Serial Question</title>
			<link href="/serial/hofmeister-changes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serial Question" />
			<updated>2016-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>karahofmeister</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Format Changing</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial/hofmeister-changes/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-everything-different&quot;&gt;Why is everything different&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on my pages for the newspaper, I continually ran into issues regarding the
financial tables. Almost every single one of mine was very different from the
templates provided and it was super frustrating and time consuming to change them all.
Because of this, my serial question for the project will be the following:
How does the format of financial tables change throughout the year?
To do this, I will look at the financial tables of numerous issues from different months,
particularly the daily weather reports and stock exchanges because those are the ones
I noticed the most differences in for my issue. I will write about the discrepancies
and use pictures of the financial tables to show the difference. This project will
show how the newspaper evolved throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial" />
			
			
				<category term="changes" />
			
				<category term="boilerplates" />
			
				<category term="financial tables" />
			

			<published>2016-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Fling-Sports/</id>
			<title>Odd Football Score</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Fling-Sports/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Odd Football Score" />
			<updated>2016-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>AmberFling</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Such a unrealistic score.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Fling-Sports/">&lt;p&gt;On November 20, 1905 the Egyptian Gazette posted a section about football at the bottom left corner of Page three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Zealander Football team is the best of the best. In London, on November 18, as suspected, they won another game with the score of 624 to 22. This is a very odd fact because the game of football usually can not reach such high point counts. Unsure of why the score was so high, I began to wonder if “football” really meant the game of football…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1905, the New Zealander Football team was most likely a Rugby team. This is inferred by the time period of the newspaper, and also the location of Alexandria. Rugby is a form of football, but not the original game we play here in the States. The objective of Rugby is to carry and/or kick a ball over the other team’s goal line. There are a few ways to score in rugby: try = 5 points, conversion goal = 2 points, penalty goal = 3 points, drop goal = 3 points. Being such small increments of points, it’s questionable how the New Zealanders team scored 624 points in this game recorded in the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This area was known for their interest in sporting activities. Often, sporting events are mentioned in the Egyptian Gazette. This shows that the demand for sporting information and updates was at a high demand in the Alexandria area. The community, as a whole, enjoyed the sporting events and kept up with their favorite team’s Win/Loss ratio through the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="Curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Football" />
			
				<category term="New Zealander Team" />
			

			<published>2016-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/cooper-technical/</id>
			<title>Issues with the Issue</title>
			<link href="/technical/cooper-technical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Issues with the Issue" />
			<updated>2016-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>MatthewCooper</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Various issues I&#39;ve encountered while attempting to digitize my portion of the Egyptian Gazette</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/cooper-technical/">&lt;p&gt;This stuff is harder than it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most of the people in this class, I have came across a formidable amount of problems while trying to do basically every step of this project. When I first began scanning my images for OCR, the first two columns of each of my page threes were blurred out so I had to go back to the library to re-scan the images more times than seemed necessary. To add to the latter, the &lt;em&gt;AABBY&lt;/em&gt; software was not the best at recognizing the characters, ergo, it was a long and gruesome process to correct all of the errors. Formatting the edited text into TEI was quite difficult as well due to the fact that this is my first time working with code. Had this class been offered for more than one semester, it may have been feasible to accomplish everything listed in the syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="Technical" />
			
			

			<published>2016-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20questions/Stefonek-Some-Serial-Food-For-Thought/</id>
			<title>Some *Cereal* Food for Thought</title>
			<link href="/serial%20questions/Stefonek-Some-Serial-Food-For-Thought/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some *Cereal* Food for Thought" />
			<updated>2016-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JacobStefonek</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Following navies around the world in 1905</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20questions/Stefonek-Some-Serial-Food-For-Thought/">&lt;p&gt;My serial discovery is that of reported military naval movements, particularly the movements of the Russian and Japanese fleets as a result of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/event/Russo-Japanese-War&quot;&gt;Russo-Japanse War&lt;/a&gt;. My goal is to use key words such as: “navy, battle, combat, fleet, ship, military, Nebogatoff, Tago and Rodjestvensky”, to find entries in the year of 1905. After finding as many entries as possible from the Egyptian Gazette, I will put together a spreadsheet that lists the report type (civilian or official), date, location and affiliation of each fleet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/The-Baltic-Fleet.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;The Baltic Fleet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, there will be additional information like the admiral(s) present with each fleet, the number, names and types of ships and any losses if a battle has occurred. Any information that is lacking in the newspaper can hopefully be supplemented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/russian-fleet-surrenders-at-port-arthur&quot;&gt;outside historical records&lt;/a&gt;. After collecting and organizing the data, I plan on using Google maps to plot the location and movements of the fleets, which will then be tagged with all of the non-locational data. That way, there will be a spiderweb across a map of the oceans linking points that can be clicked on for all available information on what happened there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial questions" />
			
			
				<category term="Navies" />
			
				<category term="Russia" />
			
				<category term="Japan" />
			
				<category term="1905" />
			

			<published>2016-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>