<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
	<updated>2018-01-05T09:04:40-05:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Will Hanley</name>
			
			
				<email>whanley@fsu.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://nationality-history.info/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.2">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Frazier-RainInTheDesert-Jordan/</id>
			<title>Rain in the Desert</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Frazier-RainInTheDesert-Jordan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rain in the Desert" />
			<updated>2017-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>jordanfrazier</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>How is the driest place in the world one of the most fertile?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Frazier-RainInTheDesert-Jordan/">&lt;p&gt;People often think of the Nile River as one of the most fertile places in the world. As a result, many colonies and cities sprouted up. Historically, humans tend to colonize towards large bodies of fresh water such as rivers or lakes because it is essential for life. However, a desert doesn’t seem like a great location to live or get a good supply of fresh water. Alexandria, Egypt is one of those exceptions. On May 30th, 1906, according to their Daily Weather Reports, Alexandria received 0.05 rainfall. It started off with a change in the wind direction from East to West, and the air became very electric. Vivid lightning strikes lit up the sky as thunder came booming in and the clouds began precipitating. While it may not be much, it still rained in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rain is not a phenomenon many people are too pleased with; however, rain brings much more benefits, especially in the desert than some may think. With rainfall, there tends to be a decrease in the high temperature, an increase in the low temperature, cool winds, as well as an increased chance of the Nile flooding in the future. While flooding certainly does not sound good for most, in Alexandria, Egypt, when the Nile floods, it fertilizes the land making it ideal for growing crops. The more floods there are, the more fertile the land is; therefore, the more food that can be grow. Maybe living in the desert is not a bad idea after all. Besides, living in Florida heat has given me an advantage!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="weather" />
			

			<published>2017-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/chacon-gorki/</id>
			<title>Maxim Gorki</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/chacon-gorki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maxim Gorki" />
			<updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Gisellechacon</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Maxim Gorki is to be prosecuted</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/chacon-gorki/">&lt;p&gt;Something that has caught my eye while reading these articles from March 1905 to April 1905 is that on the first issue on the third day, there is a small article about a man by the name of Maxim Gorki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says he is to be prosecuted because charges have been given to him that he drafted proclamations aiming to overthrow the existing state of the Empire. It also says his health has broken down and that he is liable to three years of detention in a fortress. It also then gives the day of the trial. Gorki is said to be in a place called Riga and is under surveillance. I find this curious because I would like to know more information on this matter. I would also like to know how the trial ended up. I also find it curious because it is such a small article about this man’s prosecution. I would think it would be longer. I would also like to know about the place, Riga, that he is in and if he is such a dangerous criminal that he has to be under surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="murder" />
			
				<category term="prison" />
			
				<category term="prosecution" />
			

			<published>2017-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Muniz-Thats-My-Good-Arm/</id>
			<title>Hey That&#39;s My Good Arm!</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Muniz-Thats-My-Good-Arm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hey That&#39;s My Good Arm!" />
			<updated>2017-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>AnthonyMuniz</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A deep and intellectual discussion on the horrors of life</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Muniz-Thats-My-Good-Arm/">&lt;p&gt;Remember that crappy day you had, like yesterday? or how about the time you lost your phone for an hour? Those were horrible times, but at least you didn’t lose your favorite arm like Baron London Bavastro de Cortazzi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Baron&#39;s-Arm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Newspaper Head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started over a dispute over an allegedly unpaid bill at a hotel while in the United States. He had gotten into an argument with the proprietor of the Grayson Hotel and in anger he barged out and forgot his arm in a trunk that he had left. Realizing his mistake he went into the hotel and tried to retrieve it, only to get arrested (damn Americans). Now you’re thinking that it’s only just an arm, I mean what does an arm really do, but you don’t understand how pristine this arm is. It is described by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as “Probably no better left arm can be found in this country than the one which the Baron had. It is almost human, although it is made of papier maché, aluminium, steel and wax.” They also state the usefulness saying, “The hand of it could twirl a cigarette, write checks and carry a cane”. That is the equivalent of losing an Iphone 7! Not only does the baron have to deal with his lost arm, his arrest, but he also has to deal with being a witness to the death of one his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with all of this the newspaper seems to be mocking Baron de Cortazzi, they take the upmost pleasure in using puns to describe his ordeal, “His heart is in Egypt”, “he declares that his neck has felt the heel of the oppressor”, and “through various legal complications he has nearly lost his head”. Talk about a crappy day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on a serious note who is Baron Cortazzi? Baron Cortazzi was a man who was testifying about a murder that happened to Mrs. Blanche Turner Dennis. His dad apparently owned estates in Egypt and was friends with Arlbett Sackey. His dad must have known some important people because he met Sackey through an unnamed high official in Egypt. He stated that Mrs. Blanche Turner Dennis was Sackey’s fiancée. Baron Cortazzi said that Sackey beat her once and that she may have died from that beating. No other reports could be found of Baron Cortazzi even through x-path query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that Sackey denied any role in Mrs. Dennis’ death and that someone else was accused of her murder.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Arm" />
			
				<category term="Baron London Bavastro de Cortazzi" />
			
				<category term="Mr. Potato Head" />
			

			<published>2017-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/ali-blog/</id>
			<title>Madame Butterfly: A Metamorphosis</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/ali-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madame Butterfly: A Metamorphosis" />
			<updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>TajAli</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A great play for the grand stage</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/ali-blog/">&lt;p&gt;The lights dim and slowly, the onlooking crowd goes quiet with growing anticipation. The excitable people among the bunch murmur about their excitement to see Signora Pandolfini for their first time as they prepare to hear her sing a soft melody. The people gushing with anticipation hurriedly tell them to shush as they do not want to miss the moment her voice first chirps. The curtains open and just as fast, the tale begins. It’s poetry in motion… sort of. If the crowd’s reaction was anything to go off, Pandolfini really missed the mark on the first act of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicwithease.com/puccini-butterfly-story.html&quot;&gt;Madame Butterfly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,a relatively well-known play back in the early 1900s and even now. Back in the early 1900s, the performance had been making the rounds across America and Europe, and it soon found a troop to replicate its excellence in Egypt’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cairoopera.org/history.php?lan=En&quot;&gt;Khedivial Opera House&lt;/a&gt; … for the most part at least. Pandolfini managed to win the crowd over in acts two and three, but the long-awaited play certainly had more than one mishap. While the symphonies played were engaging, many critics said that it left no real impression. This does not equate to bad though, as these same critics believed that the play was truly worthy of playing in the Khedival Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;source-of-interest&quot;&gt;Source of Interest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached here is the act by act synopsis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.columbia.edu/itc/music/NYCO/butterfly/synopsis.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madame
 Butterfly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/MadameB2.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="theater" />
			

			<published>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/</id>
			<title>Women Are Always Lying?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women Are Always Lying?" />
			<updated>2017-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>TannerDoring</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Someone had a bad breakup...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/">&lt;p&gt;While finishing the Tuesday edition of my week, I came across an article titled “Women and Lying.” This article was not only random, but shocking in how aggressive it felt. The article talked about how “women lie more constantly, laboriously, and cleverly than men, and in larger proportion.” The author of this article is very meticulous about describing how women lie. Not only does he mention how women lie through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vintagevictorian.com/costume_1905.html&quot;&gt;changing their appearances&lt;/a&gt;, but also how they lie through their feelings, their views, and their tastes. The author then goes onto describe how a woman will lie to alienate your feelings, convincing you to open up your “heavy gate” and walking right in.  It is concluded that the more a wife lies, the smoother the marriage goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was the article that stood out to me the most within my entire week. Not only was it aggressive, but it was very detailed in how, according to the author, women are very successful liars in almost every aspect of life. Without a doubt, reading this could teach you a lot about how women are viewed in the early 1900’s. It’s clear that women were not viewed as equals at this time and did not receive the respect that they had deserved. You can also learn from this the type of articles that were considered acceptable to write about in the paper when there was nothing else important to report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related blog post by MELIZZA BLACK: &lt;a href=&quot;“Avoid Female Society”&quot;&gt;“Avoid Female Society”&lt;/a&gt; Is this the female society that we are trying to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="women" />
			

			<published>2017-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/migdalski-plague/</id>
			<title>The Plague</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/migdalski-plague/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Plague" />
			<updated>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>MarsellaMigdalski</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Origins, treatment, cure?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/migdalski-plague/">&lt;p&gt;In this short newspaper article on the third page of the first day of my issue, the topic was about a plague outbreak that had numerous cases throughout Egypt. Victims of the plague had been reported dead in a number of villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article states some, but not all, of the cases were said to be pneumonic, which means it affected the lungs. This creates a curiosity for me. If only the majority of the deaths were caused by pneumonia, I wonder if all of the people who died, were infected by the same disease.  I am also curious if the disease affected different people in different ways. The article explicitly states that they deemed this plague to be contracted through direct contact. I am curious as to the origins of this plague and the characteristics and symptoms of it as well. I searched for outside information regarding this plague and &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=r_YDAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA3&amp;amp;lpg=PA3&amp;amp;dq=plague+in+egypt+1906&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=HqzdiEyewX&amp;amp;sig=7Ev85udX7QZKFaTyZEzkBb7ZukY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD79H4pMLSAhXEOSYKHcjnDo4Q6AEIIjAB#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=plague%20in%20egypt%201906&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;explains that this plague had affected other countries as well such as India, South America, and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the article talks about improvements made in a village where numerous cases of the plague occurred as well as providing treatment to one infected patient that led to their cure. This proves that the medical professionals of Egypt were able to identify the disease and develop a treatment that helped cure at least one patient. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ancient.eu/article/51/&quot;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; explains how diseases were treated in ancient Egypt. People were still exposed to similar diseases that are found today, however, their treatment methods were much different. They used medicines and “magic” which referred to asking the gods for treatment. They also made their own medical remedies, many of which contained beer which was believed to have powerful curing effects. I am interested to know how they treated and cured the single patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, medical practices in ancient Egypt have a lasting effect on present methods. Through further research, &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorable.com/ancient-medicine&quot;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; went into detail on how treatments in ancient Egypt influenced treatments used today. For example, ancient Egyptian professionals used various herbs to create medicines to cure diseases and sicknesses. Many of these same remedies are still used today. Ancient medical practices were more advanced than I presumed. There is evidence that Egyptian doctors performed eye surgery, dentistry, used prosthetics, healed broken bones, and more. Many of their treatment and healing methods were published in books that are still being preserved today. It is interesting that medical practices used in ancient times are still being used in one way or another in modern times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of my classmates and students in the past also inquired questions regarding the plague. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/rymer-plague/&quot;&gt;One student&lt;/a&gt; was also curious to know more about the plague, its origins, symptoms, and treatment. I searched through various blog posts that were written on the plague and noticed a trend. Multiple students were wondering why there was not much information on the plague. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/&quot;&gt;This student&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the small number of reports that were made about the plague. In my issue there was only one small article hidden on the third page. This makes me question how serious the disease was at the time and if it was something that either was not a major threat or if it was being hidden from the public. This is something I hope to learn more about as I continue working with my week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to go through my week in this newspaper, I hope to find more information about this plague. I wonder if the number of deaths will decreases and if a fully effective cure is developed to prevent further infections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="plague" />
			
				<category term="death" />
			
				<category term="treatment" />
			

			<published>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/</id>
			<title>Death of Haicalis Pasha</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death of Haicalis Pasha" />
			<updated>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JacobBaenen</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The passing of the Doyen of Local Press, a beloved soul and very important man in Egypt.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/">&lt;p&gt;When reading my week of the Egyptian Gazette, I came across the sad news of the Death of Haicalis Pasha. At first I didn’t know why it was so important but then continuing in the article published I could tell that Egypt lost an important life in the European Press of Egypt. He was known as the “Doyen of the Local Press” which means “the most prominent and respected person in a particular field”.  This got me interested in this man’s life and accomplishments so I started to do some research on him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haicalis earned a Doctorate of Law, was on many Governmental Administrations, was the one who persuaded Mr. Cook, the owner of Thos. Cook &amp;amp; Son tourist agency, an agency which if you have worked with the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; I’m sure you have heard of, to come to Egypt to start his business. In my own opinion, his most important accomplishment was that he was a founder and the Editor of a newspaper called &lt;em&gt;Phare d’Alexadrie&lt;/em&gt;. This paper was known for its “journalistic decency” and not blackmailing individuals, providing readers with just news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was honored in many countries for his work, receiving things like the Legion of Honor, the Order of the Crown of Italy, and many other decorations/honors. He was an important figure in the journalist community and impacted how European Press was constructed in delivering news from Egypt and inversely impacted the Egyptian Gazette.  Even though this doesn’t impact everyday life ultimately in Egypt it still is a very saddening passing of someone who made positive changes to many things in the world. This article gives me more connection to the Egyptian Gazette and makes you realize how much is going on around the world that isn’t reported on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Death" />
			
				<category term="Famous" />
			
				<category term="Journalist" />
			

			<published>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/</id>
			<title>6,000 Birds Found Dead</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6,000 Birds Found Dead" />
			<updated>2017-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>KevinFitzpatrick</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Don&#39;t go towards the light!</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/">&lt;p&gt;I came across a morbidly funny article when reading through my week of the Egyptian Gazette. The title, “FATE OF 6,000 BIRDS” and to summarize the article briefly, after two nights of thick fog, nearly 6,000 birds were found dead under a lighthouse. They were attracted to the light in the fog and flew right against it. (The full article can be found in Page 4 of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/master/1905-12-18.xml&quot;&gt;Monday, December 18, 1905&lt;/a&gt; issue of the Egyptian Gazette.) Not much else is mentioned in the article, it is a rather brief memorial. This struck me as being a unique article so I decided to share it. I did a quick search on the location of the lighthouse, “Cape Grisnez” and turns out this story takes place in France! Cape Grisnez is in northern France between Wissant and Audresselles. The cape held place to a naval battle during the Napoleonic Wars in 1805, and also would play a historical role in World War II. The lighthouse was built in 1837, originally standing 46 feet tall. In 1861, the lighthouse was raised to 79 feet tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading articles from the past makes the research more interesting, you read it from the perspective of the time frame it was written, but when investigating further you get a full picture that spans past the newspaper and through to present day. It just struck me funny how such a odd story could make international news, though granted the Egyptian
Gazette was sold to an audience of mainly Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lighthousedigest.com/digest/database/uniquelighthouse.cfm?value=5327&quot;&gt;Lighthouse Digest, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.francethisway.com/places/cap-gris-blanc-nez.php&quot;&gt;France This Way, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unc.edu/~rowlett/lighthouse/fran.htm&quot;&gt;University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Lighthouses of France, North Coast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="birds" />
			
				<category term="Cape Grisnez" />
			
				<category term="lighthouse" />
			
				<category term="fog" />
			
				<category term="France" />
			

			<published>2017-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/bolton-blog/</id>
			<title>Pe-ru-na</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/bolton-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pe-ru-na" />
			<updated>2017-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>madisonbolton</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Oldest Man in America</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/bolton-blog/">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; on March 15, 1905 there was a man named Mr. Isaac Brock, and he was 115 years old and claiming to be the oldest man in America.  Mr. Brock lived in McLennan County, Texas, and he accredited his old age of the use of a medicine called “Pe-ru-na.” The article lists facts about Mr. Brock’s life including “born before the United States was formed, saw 22 Presidents elected, shod a horse when 99 years old.” People were so mesmerized by the extent of Mr. Brock’s age that he even wrote a “lengthy biographical sketch,” and he was written about in the &lt;em&gt;Dallas Morning News&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Chicago-Times&lt;/em&gt;.  Mr. Brock claims that Peruna protects him from sudden changes, and it is the greatest remedy for adapting to changes and the age of “catarrhal disease.”  Catarrhal diseases are what we call now Bronchitis or an excess of mucus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peruna was invented by Dr. Samuel Brubaker Hartman who actually preferred the name PE-RU-NA. After researching to find out what PE-RU-NA actually is, I found that it is a tonic that contains 18% alcohol.  It became popular after prohibition, when states went “dry” and banned all alcohol. It was still able to be sold over the counter, and became very popular that is was referred to as the “Prohibition Tonic.” It was so popular that people even named their children after it, and Southern Methodist University named their mascot of a black mustang horse Peruna.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="peruna" />
			
				<category term="America" />
			
				<category term="oldest man" />
			
				<category term="Texas" />
			

			<published>2017-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/</id>
			<title>Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?" />
			<updated>2017-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>WilliamOrtiz</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The Egyptian Gazette is reporting on anarchist activity but why is that important to British Egypt?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/">&lt;p&gt;According to the telegraphs, a man by the name of Matteo Moral, a known Anarchist, attempted to assassinate King Alfonso of Spain with a bomb. After being confronted by a police officer, Moral killed the officer. Shortly after, to evade capture, he committed suicide by shooting himself through the heart. Alongside Moral, an English tourist named Hamilton was also arrested under the charges of being an anarchist. The article does not state any more details about Hamilton’s arrest other than the Spanish authority refused to release him to the British.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Russian-Anarchy.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Russian Anarchy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that the assassination attempt happened in Spain but it is being reported on by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in British Egypt. Why is anarchist activity important to the British? Before communism was the boogeyman of Europe, anarchism seemed to be the ideology that was branded the enemy of the state. A year prior to this assassination attempt, the Russian state was under threat of “anarchy” during the Russo-Japanese War. That was also reported by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in an article called “IS IT PEACE” which can be located in the June 1, 1906 edition on page two. Anarchism was an ideology that threatened the state was a whole. In an age where the state extended its power through colonial empires, anarchism threatened to dismantle the colonial system by weakening the state. To Great Britain, tracking anarchist activities of competing empires is important because it is a way to evaluate how strong the enemy central state is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more general information and history on anarchism as an ideology, feel free to read Noam Chomsky’s article, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://inthesetimes.com/article/16081/a_history_of_anarchism/&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Anarchism&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Anarchist-Arrested.png&quot; alt=&quot;Anarchist Arrested&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="anarchy" />
			
				<category term="colonialism" />
			
				<category term="Russia" />
			
				<category term="tsar," />
			
				<category term="Japan" />
			

			<published>2017-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>