<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
	<updated>2017-05-01T22:42:10-04:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Will Hanley</name>
			
			
				<email>whanley@fsu.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://nationality-history.info/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.2">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/</id>
			<title>Women Are Always Lying?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women Are Always Lying?" />
			<updated>2017-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>TannerDoring</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Someone had a bad breakup...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/">&lt;p&gt;While finishing the Tuesday edition of my week, I came across an article titled “Women and Lying.” This article was not only random, but shocking in how aggressive it felt. The article talked about how “women lie more constantly, laboriously, and cleverly than men, and in larger proportion.” The author of this article is very meticulous about describing how women lie. Not only does he mention how women lie through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vintagevictorian.com/costume_1905.html&quot;&gt;changing their appearances&lt;/a&gt;, but also how they lie through their feelings, their views, and their tastes. The author then goes onto describe how a woman will lie to alienate your feelings, convincing you to open up your “heavy gate” and walking right in.  It is concluded that the more a wife lies, the smoother the marriage goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was the article that stood out to me the most within my entire week. Not only was it aggressive, but it was very detailed in how, according to the author, women are very successful liars in almost every aspect of life. Without a doubt, reading this could teach you a lot about how women are viewed in the early 1900’s. It’s clear that women were not viewed as equals at this time and did not receive the respect that they had deserved. You can also learn from this the type of articles that were considered acceptable to write about in the paper when there was nothing else important to report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related blog post by MELIZZA BLACK: &lt;a href=&quot;“Avoid Female Society”&quot;&gt;“Avoid Female Society”&lt;/a&gt; Is this the female society that we are trying to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="women" />
			

			<published>2017-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/</id>
			<title>Death of Haicalis Pasha</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death of Haicalis Pasha" />
			<updated>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JacobBaenen</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The passing of the Doyen of Local Press, a beloved soul and very important man in Egypt.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Baenen-DeathofThePasha/">&lt;p&gt;When reading my week of the Egyptian Gazette, I came across the sad news of the Death of Haicalis Pasha. At first I didn’t know why it was so important but then continuing in the article published I could tell that Egypt lost an important life in the European Press of Egypt. He was known as the “Doyen of the Local Press” which means “the most prominent and respected person in a particular field”.  This got me interested in this man’s life and accomplishments so I started to do some research on him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haicalis earned a Doctorate of Law, was on many Governmental Administrations, was the one who persuaded Mr. Cook, the owner of Thos. Cook &amp;amp; Son tourist agency, an agency which if you have worked with the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; I’m sure you have heard of, to come to Egypt to start his business. In my own opinion, his most important accomplishment was that he was a founder and the Editor of a newspaper called &lt;em&gt;Phare d’Alexadrie&lt;/em&gt;. This paper was known for its “journalistic decency” and not blackmailing individuals, providing readers with just news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was honored in many countries for his work, receiving things like the Legion of Honor, the Order of the Crown of Italy, and many other decorations/honors. He was an important figure in the journalist community and impacted how European Press was constructed in delivering news from Egypt and inversely impacted the Egyptian Gazette.  Even though this doesn’t impact everyday life ultimately in Egypt it still is a very saddening passing of someone who made positive changes to many things in the world. This article gives me more connection to the Egyptian Gazette and makes you realize how much is going on around the world that isn’t reported on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Death" />
			
				<category term="Famous" />
			
				<category term="Journalist" />
			

			<published>2017-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/</id>
			<title>Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?" />
			<updated>2017-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>WilliamOrtiz</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The Egyptian Gazette is reporting on anarchist activity but why is that important to British Egypt?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Ortiz-Russian-Anarchy/">&lt;p&gt;According to the telegraphs, a man by the name of Matteo Moral, a known Anarchist, attempted to assassinate King Alfonso of Spain with a bomb. After being confronted by a police officer, Moral killed the officer. Shortly after, to evade capture, he committed suicide by shooting himself through the heart. Alongside Moral, an English tourist named Hamilton was also arrested under the charges of being an anarchist. The article does not state any more details about Hamilton’s arrest other than the Spanish authority refused to release him to the British.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Russian-Anarchy.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Russian Anarchy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that the assassination attempt happened in Spain but it is being reported on by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in British Egypt. Why is anarchist activity important to the British? Before communism was the boogeyman of Europe, anarchism seemed to be the ideology that was branded the enemy of the state. A year prior to this assassination attempt, the Russian state was under threat of “anarchy” during the Russo-Japanese War. That was also reported by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in an article called “IS IT PEACE” which can be located in the June 1, 1906 edition on page two. Anarchism was an ideology that threatened the state was a whole. In an age where the state extended its power through colonial empires, anarchism threatened to dismantle the colonial system by weakening the state. To Great Britain, tracking anarchist activities of competing empires is important because it is a way to evaluate how strong the enemy central state is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more general information and history on anarchism as an ideology, feel free to read Noam Chomsky’s article, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://inthesetimes.com/article/16081/a_history_of_anarchism/&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Anarchism&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Anarchist-Arrested.png&quot; alt=&quot;Anarchist Arrested&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="anarchy" />
			
				<category term="colonialism" />
			
				<category term="Russia" />
			
				<category term="tsar," />
			
				<category term="Japan" />
			

			<published>2017-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/hammermaster-dishonesty-the-consistency-of-politics/</id>
			<title>Dishonesty: The Consistency of Politics</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/hammermaster-dishonesty-the-consistency-of-politics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dishonesty: The Consistency of Politics" />
			<updated>2017-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>oliviahammermaster</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>People make careless remarks all the time, especially public figures who then regret what they said. Egyptian royalty in 1906 was no different.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/hammermaster-dishonesty-the-consistency-of-politics/">&lt;p&gt;People make careless remarks all the time, especially public figures who then regret what they said. Egyptian royalty in 1906 was no different. The Wednesday, January 31st issue devotes an entire column to the Princess Nazli to allow her to make a statement refuting a comment she had made the previous Saturday. This comment consisted of her saying Egyptians were babies and Lord Cromer “did everything.” The editor of &lt;em&gt;Al Mokattam&lt;/em&gt;, Dr. Nimr, jumped on this statement and asked the princess if she had adopted the French nationality instead. Princess Nazli then defends herself with the response that she has no desire to change her nationality, but still defends her words. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revolvy.com/topic/Princess%20Nazli%20Fazl&amp;amp;item_type=topic&quot;&gt;She was a very educated woman, which was uncharacteristic of that society, who had good experience with other cultures&lt;/a&gt;, so she knew how to defend herself. She claims that the translation in the newspaper was correct and stands by what she says, praising Lord Cromer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.egy.com/historica/queennazli.php&quot;&gt;Princess Nazli had a very involved family, many of whom were of different nationalities&lt;/a&gt;. Although she spends the beginning of her statement defending herself as an Ottoman subject, she seems to spend a lot of time talking about Lord Cromer and her father’s influence, seemingly as a distracting tactic to get off topic. Toward the end of her statement, she revisits the original issue: what she claims as her nationality. Princess Nazli almost seems to attack her critics, asking a series of questions regarding why her nationality was being challenged. The politicians of today use all these same tactics. They make it seem like they address a question while really discussing something else, then turn the conversation around to make themselves look better. I find it fascinating that this trend has persisted throughout so many decades, possibly even multiple centuries. For me, it begs the question: Will politics ever be honest?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Princess Nazli" />
			
				<category term="nationality" />
			
				<category term="French" />
			
				<category term="Ottoman" />
			
				<category term="Lord Cromer" />
			
				<category term="politics" />
			

			<published>2017-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/</id>
			<title>6,000 Birds Found Dead</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6,000 Birds Found Dead" />
			<updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>KevinFitzpatrick</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Don&#39;t go towards the light!</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/fitzpatrick-post-birds/">&lt;p&gt;I came across a morbidly funny article when reading through my week of the Egyptian Gazette. The title, “FATE OF 6,000 BIRDS” and to summarize the article briefly, after two nights of thick fog, nearly 6,000 birds were found dead under a lighthouse. They were attracted to the light in the fog and flew right against it. Not much else is mentioned in the article, it is a rather brief memorial. This struck me as being a unique article so I decided to share it. I did a quick search on the location of the lighthouse, “Cape Grisnez” and turns out this story takes place in France! Cape Grisnez is in northern France between Wissant and Audresselles. The cape held place to a naval battle during the Napoleonic Wars in 1805, and also would play a historical role in World War II. The lighthouse was built in 1837, originally standing 46 feet tall. In 1861, the lighthouse was raised to 79 feet tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading articles from the past makes the research more interesting, you read it from the perspective of the time frame it was written, but when investigating further you get a full picture that spans past the newspaper and through to present day. It just struck me funny how such a odd story could make international news, though granted the Egyptian
Gazette was sold to an audience of mainly Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lighthousedigest.com/digest/database/uniquelighthouse.cfm?value=5327&quot;&gt;Lighthouse Digest, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.francethisway.com/places/cap-gris-blanc-nez.php&quot;&gt;France This Way, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unc.edu/~rowlett/lighthouse/fran.htm&quot;&gt;University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Lighthouses of France, North Coast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="birds" />
			
				<category term="Cape Grisnez" />
			
				<category term="lighthouse" />
			
				<category term="fog" />
			
				<category term="France" />
			

			<published>2017-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/</id>
			<title>Icilma</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Icilma" />
			<updated>2017-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>SabrinaNunez</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Nature&#39;s Skin Food</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/">&lt;p&gt;To begin, the name Icilma came from combining the Arabic words ‘icil’ meaning flows and ‘mha’ meaning water.  It was Stephen Armitage who founded Icilma in 1898. He was a civil engineer who found the use in mineral water from a natural spring located in Algeria. Originally wanting to open a spa near the spring, Stephen was moving from city to city trying to sell this mineral water in any way possible. He moved from Algeria to Paris and later growing his product in London. Finally settling in London, he established the business “Nature’s Remedy Company” where he not only worked as a chemist, but also built the machinery that went on to create Icilma cream. Icilma cream then transitioned into Icilma Flour cream due to the Calcium fluoride present in the water. It was later known and advertised as ‘Nature’s Skin Food’. Not only did it heal and prevent blemishes, and blackheads, but it was also a great product for healing mosquito and insect bites as well. It was sold as both a face powder and a soap.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="skin food" />
			
				<category term="healing" />
			
				<category term="youthful" />
			
				<category term="preventing" />
			

			<published>2017-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/pearce-blog/</id>
			<title>Reading of Sentence</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/pearce-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading of Sentence" />
			<updated>2017-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>willpearce</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>In this portion of this Thursday issue of the Egyptian Gazette,</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/pearce-blog/">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the third or fourth pages always begin to get deep into the local news, including stories of crimes, births, deaths, and all sorts of events. One very historical event in Egypt took place around this time - the Denshiwai Affair. On June 26, 1906, a lot of the information being released showed how the criminal trial was beginning to unfold. The trial took place in the Denshiwai village inside of Chibin el Kom, Egypt. A bad attack occurred between rebels and officers of the police force. There was a lineup of prisoners and witnesses who could speak and defend themselves, fairly similar to that of a modern day court system. It’s crazy to think how little the judicial system varies from country to country, especially over 100 years apart, when comparing it to the modern day American system. This seems almost similar to the current Black Lives Matter movements that have occurred across the United States in recent years, as police are being beaten and attacked along with people in the streets. It is interesting how closely history repeats itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday and Thursday, June 28 and 29, 1906, respectively, the final information was reviewed and the sentences were given. The death penalty is decided as one of the most level-headed punishments for the offenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sentence of death was passed on the four following prisoners:
- Hassan Mahfouz (11)
- Youssef Hassan Salim (14)
- Said Issa Salim (25)
- Mohamed Darwish Zahran (48).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different encounters were mentioned in the case such as the possibility of premeditation, along with the death of Captain Bull, supported by any medical evidence available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“AS the crowd prevented the Major and his two comrades from getting into carriages, pulled them about and beat them, throwing bricks and dry mud at them…” I like this statement from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, as I think of it as a simile to the present-day life of a student in some ways. As a student myself, being overwhelmed with homework, exams, quizzes can really seem as if I was getting metaphorically beaten, having bricks and dry mud thrown at you. Of course, nobody should have to know the brutal beatings that Captain Bull, Lieutenant Smithwick, and Major Pine-Coffin, along with other innocent people had faced in this attack. All in all, this has been the most enjoyable part of the story of the attack at Denshiwai, as it used some very descriptive language, making it as easy as possible to see the brutal beatings that occurred on that day in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Denshiwai" />
			

			<published>2017-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/</id>
			<title>A Regatta Is a Boat Race.</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Regatta Is a Boat Race." />
			<updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>KennethUkah</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>In this week&#39;s regatta, The Ananke aims for another first place finish after her successful debut in the Khedival Yacht Club. But what does that even mean?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/">&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette will occasionally feature a “Sport and Play.” section, usually containing scores from cricket games. For the majority of this week, though, the section featured a regatta hosted by the Khedival Yacht Club. Unlike cricket, a regatta is a series of boat races, so I initially found its placement in the newspaper odd, until reading this sub article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL2.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Yachting in Alexandria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yachting has apparently found an audience in Alexandria’s sporting community, so much so that private owners with large money influences have begun to participate in races. (That is how I understand it at least.) I figured some additional research into these races was warranted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;The Motor Boat: Devoted to All Types of Power Craft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 4, Issue 12, by Francis P. Prial pg. 43: Prial mentions the waters near Alexandria and in Egypt in general as “splendid facilities for motorboating…” and how these waters were not receiving enough attention from craft owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the central theme in this source is motorboats, not yachts, I feel the source warrants mentioning because ideal waters might be a reason for the success that yachting in Alexandria had seen, and because the author also speaks highly of the Khedival Yacht Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1908 – &lt;em&gt;Encyclopaedia of Ships and Shipping&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert B. Mason, pg. 328: A general definition of the Khedival Yacht Club: “Established 1902. Patron, H. H. the Khedive of Egypt ; Commodore, H.H. Prince Aziz Pacha Hassan…Entrance fee, £3 ; annual subscription, £2.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the mention of an entrance fee, I assume that anyone could have participated in the regattas, and that the aforementioned private owners had the money to invest in elite crafts that could win races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;Fore’n’aft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, pg. 62: The Khedival Yacht Club is hailed as “the only important organization of its kind in Egypt… and now has two hundred and thirty members and a fleet of fifty yachts. Weekly regattas are held in fort and numerous enjoyable social functions at the handsome club house.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, here are the results of the week in question’s regatta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL3.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Regatta Results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ananke, a privately owned craft favored by the newspaper to win the race in its class, could not withstand the wind and waters that day, and had to forfeit the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="regatta" />
			
				<category term="race" />
			
				<category term="yacht" />
			
				<category term="club" />
			
				<category term="khedival" />
			

			<published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Fajardo-Blog/</id>
			<title>Analysis of _The Road Man_</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Fajardo-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analysis of _The Road Man_" />
			<updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>dianafajardo</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>One liner</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Fajardo-Blog/">&lt;p&gt;As a lover of fiction, I decided to pick a short story, named as &lt;em&gt;The Road Man&lt;/em&gt;, for this assignment. The story pertains to a young fellow who always noticed an &lt;strong&gt;elderly prophet&lt;/strong&gt; that always carries a hefty wheelbarrow. I was very amused to this piece because I notice many similarities between the prophet and your average college student. For instance, when the narrator mentions, “His skin, burnt almost black with sun and wind, his shaggy eyebrows and long white beard, suggest the prophets of ancient days”, reminded me of a college senior. As the prophet appears worn down from his exposure to the sun, one may compare that to how a senior appears exhausted, after years of sleep deprivation due to a tedious work load. Ironically, the narrator gave me the impression that he is a college freshman, because he is young and does not have the same years of experiences as the prophet. Many college freshman will not understand a college seniors’ desire to undertake a tedious task due to the lack of experience. However, as the years pass by, college freshmen will fulfill the seniors shoes, as the narrator will fill the prophet’s shoes. I believe this passage is very significant since it is still relevant after being composed 115 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="tag" />
			

			<published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/</id>
			<title>Plants that make ice?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plants that make ice?" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>jonathanmorales</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>See what happens when engineers mix water with plants.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/">&lt;p&gt;While going through the newspaper, OCR-ing it, and transcribing it to XML, I usually don’t pay attention to what’s written. Not because I don’t want to - but because I go through it so fast, I don’t have time to. Until I came across this interesting advertisement. At a quick glance of the page, it immediately caught my attention. Yes, the big letters aided in that, but what was in the title is what really got me puzzled. “Ice Making Plants”? I thought, there’s &lt;em&gt;no way&lt;/em&gt; they found plants that make ice. Upon continuing to read I saw it said “Power Driven Machines to produce 1 cwt. Per 24 hours” (or about 1lb ≈ every 15 mins). So now I drew another conclusion – they’ve made robotic plants that make ice instead of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this couldn’t be correct so I took it upon myself to call the number on the ad and ask – but &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I got a “Your call could not be completed as dialed” (must have been a typo). Unfortunately, they didn’t put an email I could contact so I went to my backup-backup plan and scoured the web. After adequate research, I came to my last conclusion: This misleading ad sold ice machines crankable by hand that could be used in &lt;strong&gt;factory&lt;/strong&gt; plants to produce a lot of ice. I also concluded that the “Egyptian Engineering Co., LTD.” didn’t come up with the product, it just resold it as a white label. The RAPLIN originally came from England in the 1890s made by “Pulsometer Engineering Co., LTD” which continued to manufacture ice machines and other advancements throughout the years. Who knew ~~an innocent~~ a deceptive advertisement from the early 1900s could get a person from the 21st century so well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=kBMpAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA110&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1898&quot;&gt;Ice and Refrigeration Illustrated Vol. 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=mj5FAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA233&amp;amp;lpg=RA1-PA233&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1898&quot;&gt;The Practical Engineer. Volume XVII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=cwsAAAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA20&amp;amp;lpg=PA20&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1899&quot;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XXIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/Pulsometer_Engineering_Co:_1914_Catalogue&quot; title=&quot;Catalogue of Pulsometer&#39;s machines&quot;&gt;Pulsometer Engineering Co: 1914 Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=PYdJAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA172&amp;amp;lpg=PA172&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1908&quot;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XLIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/RAPLIN_Ice_Machine_Cleaned_Up.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine&quot; /&gt; | &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Raplin_Ice_Machine_V2_Cleaned_up.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine V2&quot; /&gt;
———— | ————-&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="advertisement" />
			
				<category term="engineering" />
			
				<category term="future" />
			
				<category term="machines" />
			
				<category term="ice" />
			
				<category term="water" />
			
				<category term="refrigeration" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>