<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
	<updated>2017-05-01T18:16:50-04:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Will Hanley</name>
			
			
				<email>whanley@fsu.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://nationality-history.info/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.2">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/pearce-blog/</id>
			<title>Reading of Sentence</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/pearce-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading of Sentence" />
			<updated>2017-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>willpearce</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>In this portion of this Thursday issue of the Egyptian Gazette,</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/pearce-blog/">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the third or fourth pages always begin to get deep into the local news, including stories of crimes, births, deaths, and all sorts of events. One very historical event in Egypt took place around this time - the Denshiwai Affair. On June 26, 1906, a lot of the information being released showed how the criminal trial was beginning to unfold. The trial took place in the Denshiwai village inside of Chibin el Kom, Egypt. A bad attack occurred between rebels and officers of the police force. There was a lineup of prisoners and witnesses who could speak and defend themselves, fairly similar to that of a modern day court system. It’s crazy to think how little the judicial system varies from country to country, especially over 100 years apart, when comparing it to the modern day American system. This seems almost similar to the current Black Lives Matter movements that have occurred across the United States in recent years, as police are being beaten and attacked along with people in the streets. It is interesting how closely history repeats itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday and Thursday, June 28 and 29, 1906, respectively, the final information was reviewed and the sentences were given. The death penalty is decided as one of the most level-headed punishments for the offenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sentence of death was passed on the four following prisoners:
- Hassan Mahfouz (11)
- Youssef Hassan Salim (14)
- Said Issa Salim (25)
- Mohamed Darwish Zahran (48).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different encounters were mentioned in the case such as the possibility of premeditation, along with the death of Captain Bull, supported by any medical evidence available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“AS the crowd prevented the Major and his two comrades from getting into carriages, pulled them about and beat them, throwing bricks and dry mud at them…” I like this statement from the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, as I think of it as a simile to the present-day life of a student in some ways. As a student myself, being overwhelmed with homework, exams, quizzes can really seem as if I was getting metaphorically beaten, having bricks and dry mud thrown at you. Of course, nobody should have to know the brutal beatings that Captain Bull, Lieutenant Smithwick, and Major Pine-Coffin, along with other innocent people had faced in this attack. All in all, this has been the most enjoyable part of the story of the attack at Denshiwai, as it used some very descriptive language, making it as easy as possible to see the brutal beatings that occurred on that day in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Denshiwai" />
			

			<published>2017-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/</id>
			<title>A Regatta Is a Boat Race.</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Regatta Is a Boat Race." />
			<updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>KennethUkah</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>In this week&#39;s regatta, The Ananke aims for another first place finish after her successful debut in the Khedival Yacht Club. But what does that even mean?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/">&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette will occasionally feature a “Sport and Play.” section, usually containing scores from cricket games. For the majority of this week, though, the section featured a regatta hosted by the Khedival Yacht Club. Unlike cricket, a regatta is a series of boat races, so I initially found its placement in the newspaper odd, until reading this sub article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL2.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Yachting in Alexandria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yachting has apparently found an audience in Alexandria’s sporting community, so much so that private owners with large money influences have begun to participate in races. (That is how I understand it at least.) I figured some additional research into these races was warranted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;The Motor Boat: Devoted to All Types of Power Craft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 4, Issue 12, by Francis P. Prial pg. 43: Prial mentions the waters near Alexandria and in Egypt in general as “splendid facilities for motorboating…” and how these waters were not receiving enough attention from craft owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the central theme in this source is motorboats, not yachts, I feel the source warrants mentioning because ideal waters might be a reason for the success that yachting in Alexandria had seen, and because the author also speaks highly of the Khedival Yacht Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1908 – &lt;em&gt;Encyclopaedia of Ships and Shipping&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert B. Mason, pg. 328: A general definition of the Khedival Yacht Club: “Established 1902. Patron, H. H. the Khedive of Egypt ; Commodore, H.H. Prince Aziz Pacha Hassan…Entrance fee, £3 ; annual subscription, £2.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the mention of an entrance fee, I assume that anyone could have participated in the regattas, and that the aforementioned private owners had the money to invest in elite crafts that could win races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;Fore’n’aft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, pg. 62: The Khedival Yacht Club is hailed as “the only important organization of its kind in Egypt… and now has two hundred and thirty members and a fleet of fifty yachts. Weekly regattas are held in fort and numerous enjoyable social functions at the handsome club house.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, here are the results of the week in question’s regatta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL3.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Regatta Results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ananke, a privately owned craft favored by the newspaper to win the race in its class, could not withstand the wind and waters that day, and had to forfeit the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="regatta" />
			
				<category term="race" />
			
				<category term="yacht" />
			
				<category term="club" />
			
				<category term="khedival" />
			

			<published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/</id>
			<title>Plants that make ice?</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plants that make ice?" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>jonathanmorales</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>See what happens when engineers mix water with plants.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/morales-plants-that-make-ICE/">&lt;p&gt;While going through the newspaper, OCR-ing it, and transcribing it to XML, I usually don’t pay attention to what’s written. Not because I don’t want to - but because I go through it so fast, I don’t have time to. Until I came across this interesting advertisement. At a quick glance of the page, it immediately caught my attention. Yes, the big letters aided in that, but what was in the title is what really got me puzzled. “Ice Making Plants”? I thought, there’s &lt;em&gt;no way&lt;/em&gt; they found plants that make ice. Upon continuing to read I saw it said “Power Driven Machines to produce 1 cwt. Per 24 hours” (or about 1lb ≈ every 15 mins). So now I drew another conclusion – they’ve made robotic plants that make ice instead of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this couldn’t be correct so I took it upon myself to call the number on the ad and ask – but &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; I got a “Your call could not be completed as dialed” (must have been a typo). Unfortunately, they didn’t put an email I could contact so I went to my backup-backup plan and scoured the web. After adequate research, I came to my last conclusion: This misleading ad sold ice machines crankable by hand that could be used in &lt;strong&gt;factory&lt;/strong&gt; plants to produce a lot of ice. I also concluded that the “Egyptian Engineering Co., LTD.” didn’t come up with the product, it just resold it as a white label. The RAPLIN originally came from England in the 1890s made by “Pulsometer Engineering Co., LTD” which continued to manufacture ice machines and other advancements throughout the years. Who knew ~~an innocent~~ a deceptive advertisement from the early 1900s could get a person from the 21st century so well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=kBMpAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA110&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1898&quot;&gt;Ice and Refrigeration Illustrated Vol. 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=mj5FAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA233&amp;amp;lpg=RA1-PA233&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1898&quot;&gt;The Practical Engineer. Volume XVII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=cwsAAAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA20&amp;amp;lpg=PA20&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1899&quot;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XXIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/Pulsometer_Engineering_Co:_1914_Catalogue&quot; title=&quot;Catalogue of Pulsometer&#39;s machines&quot;&gt;Pulsometer Engineering Co: 1914 Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=PYdJAQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA172&amp;amp;lpg=PA172&quot; title=&quot;Printed 1908&quot;&gt;The Chemical Trade Journal: Volume XLIII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/RAPLIN_Ice_Machine_Cleaned_Up.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine&quot; /&gt; | &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Raplin_Ice_Machine_V2_Cleaned_up.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;RAPLIN Hand Ice Machine V2&quot; /&gt;
———— | ————-&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="advertisement" />
			
				<category term="engineering" />
			
				<category term="future" />
			
				<category term="machines" />
			
				<category term="ice" />
			
				<category term="water" />
			
				<category term="refrigeration" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/flick-H-&-C-Flick,-Cigar-Importers/</id>
			<title>H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/flick-H-&-C-Flick,-Cigar-Importers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>madisonflick</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Am I related?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/flick-H-&-C-Flick,-Cigar-Importers/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egyptian_cigarette_industry#cite_note-5&quot;&gt;Egyptian cigarette industry&lt;/a&gt; was one of the main exports in Egypt during the time period from the 1880s to the end of the World War I. Just from reading one week of issues of the Egyptian Gazette, I could tell that cigarettes were a major part of an Egyptian’s life. There was at least one advertisement for cigarettes on each page of the newspaper, but one specific advertisement in particular stood out to me the most: “H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, Cigar Importers.” Now this specific ad might not sound important to anyone else, but to me it was very interesting and got me thinking about my ancestry. I am 99.9% sure that I am not related to these Flick’s, but I wonder what it would be like to be a Flick in Egypt in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1905, Egypt imported a total of 8,078 tonnes of tobacco and a total of 8,377 tonnes in 1906 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=qs_YlWuFjooC&amp;amp;lpg=PR3&amp;amp;pg=PA59#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Relli Shechter, &lt;em&gt;Smoking, Culture and Economy in the Middle East: The Egyptian Tobacco Market 1850-2000&lt;/em&gt;, p. 59 &lt;/a&gt;). The advertisement states that H. &amp;amp; C. Flick was the largest depot of cigars in Egypt, so I can imagine that Flick’s were a very successful in 1906 due to the increase in cigar imports from 1905 to 1906.  Egyptian tobacco was usually very poorly made and didn’t taste very well, so most of the cigarettes in Egypt were not made from Egyptian tobacco (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41339516?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES AND TOBACCO, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Society of Arts&lt;/em&gt; Vol. 59, No. 3034 (JANUARY 13, 1911), pp. 201-203&lt;/a&gt;). Due to Egyptian tobacco not being up to par with what most tourists and immigrants are used to, being a cigarette importer was probably a very good business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I might not actually be related to H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, I now know that it would probably be a good family business in Egypt in 1906, but it might be harder to be a cigar importer in the United States in 2017 due to all the information about how terrible cigarettes are for our health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Blog Post by ALEX CALIENDO: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&quot;&gt;The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="advertisement" />
			
				<category term="cigar" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Story-TheUntimelyDeathofPrinceMohamidIbrahim/</id>
			<title>The Untimely Death of Prince Mohamed Ibrahim</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Story-TheUntimelyDeathofPrinceMohamidIbrahim/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Untimely Death of Prince Mohamed Ibrahim" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JoshuaStory</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Freak Car Accident</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Story-TheUntimelyDeathofPrinceMohamidIbrahim/">&lt;p&gt;The cousin of H.H. the Khedive, Prince Mohamed Ibrahim, was killed along with his driver in a rather unusual car accident. The accident report stated that his driver was speeding, and collided with a train. It is incredibly rare to see train/car collisions spurring from speeding as opposed to a car stopped on the tracks. This incident makes me wonder what exactly was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was a matter of sheer stupidity on account of the driver? Did he think he could outrun a train, or make it past the tracks before it got there? Was the Prince in a rush to be somewhere? It was on a Saturday night so maybe the driver had a little too much of that Hashish. It is baffling that out of all the things he could have collided with it was a train. In order to be a fatal crash, he had to have most likely come in to contact with the front of the train. This was not even his first car accident. He was also involved in a car accident a year earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first crash, the Prince probably should have taken the hint that his driver was not very skilled at his profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="-car" />
			
				<category term="accidents" />
			
				<category term="-famous" />
			
				<category term="death" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Rodriguez-blog/</id>
			<title>Dead Man, One Horse</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Rodriguez-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dead Man, One Horse" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>CarlosRodriguez</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A murderous horse vs. the common thief</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Rodriguez-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Murders overall aren’t that common, so it was even more surprising when I found out that there was a murderous horse on the loose! On July 7, 1906, it was reported that a man sneaked into the yard of a resident. Even though his intentions were never discovered it is assumed by the article that his sole goal was to steal a horse. When in the process of untying the ropes of the animal, the horse kicked him square in the face, killing him instantly. This is one thief that never got a second chance. It makes me wonder if there are any other murderous animals in Alexandria, other than the everyday man. If it wasn’t for the horse killing him I believe the owner would have killed him if caught. I came to this conclusion after reading many articles having to do with thieves and criminals. Even if it wasn’t the owner the police would have surely caught him because according to the newspaper they have an excellent arrest rate. Yet the fate of this poor man was surely set the minute he decided to trespass on someone’s property. Upon reading this I am almost certain that thieves all over the city were either scared of stealing any more horses, or that they were just more careful when stealing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="animals" />
			
				<category term="crime" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Barrett-Donkey-Drivers/</id>
			<title>Donkey Drivers</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Barrett-Donkey-Drivers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Donkey Drivers" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>ElizabethBarrett</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The perfume mall-kiosks salesmen of the early 1900s</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Barrett-Donkey-Drivers/">&lt;p&gt;You see them on the horizon. Look down. Avoid Eye Contact. Do not acknowledge them. Fake a phone call. Start crying. Alas, your effort is futile. Whether you like it or not, the dreaded moment will come where you are clotheslined by an arm trying to get you to buy perfume from their kiosk in the middle of the mall. Turns out, this isn’t just a modern day frustration - we’ve been suffering worldwide for over 100 years, minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although 1905 Cairo didn’t have an infestation of pushy perfume salesmen, they did have “donkey boys”. These guys would call after you, bothering you, insisting you use their donkeys to get to your next location. Our complainer who wrote the correspondent was offended they’d think he’d even consider taking anything but a cab. Donkey boys seem like our kiosk worker on steroids; the only thing that’s stopping the residents of Cairo from hitting them is the fact that there’s a police officer too close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution sought is to get a &lt;em&gt;shawish&lt;/em&gt; (meaning Police or Army Sergeant) to make a law against their badgering solicitation. As the complainer remarks, ““No reproof has any effect unless it be to bring a flow of filthy language”… which might be the most British way to say “cussing them out is all that works!”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Donkey" />
			
				<category term="sell" />
			
				<category term="complaints" />
			
				<category term="Cairo" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/212-runs/</id>
			<title>212 Runs</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/212-runs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="212 Runs" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>jaimesepulveda</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A complete thrashing (or is it?)</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/212-runs/">&lt;p&gt;I have never watched a game of cricket in my life, but I had always assumed it was somewhat similar to baseball. A reasonable assumption I would say, as it features the same general idea of guy throwing ball and other guy trying to hit ball. Just that the ball bounces and you are allowed to hit it backwards, apparently. Then I saw the phrase “Somerset beat Glousestershire by 212 runs”. Well that seems like a rather large number. I realized it was time for some detective work: was this simply a thorough butt-whooping like never seen before, or do the rules of cricket make this a reasonable margin of victory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=AqtpNkMvj5Y&quot;&gt;this short video&lt;/a&gt;, several revelations have been made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Runs are much easier to come by than in baseball.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home runs are 6 runs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doubles off the wall are 4 runs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 outs instead of 3 outs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Balls” count as a run.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Balks” count as a run.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First base is only 66 feet away as opposed to the usual 90.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Singles are runs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Games can potentially last up to 5 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then. I guess losing by 212 runs isn’t as bad as it seems. Still, a crushing loss for Glousestershire. Watch out for this Somerset squad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="sports" />
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Anderson-BubonicPlague/</id>
			<title>The Bubonic Plague</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Anderson-BubonicPlague/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bubonic Plague" />
			<updated>2017-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>AlizaAnderson</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>How the Bubonic Plague hit Egypt</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Anderson-BubonicPlague/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bubonic-plague-has-arrived&quot;&gt;The Bubonic Plague has Arrived&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Striking Now in Egypt
Spread by Rats and Fleas
The Bubonic Plague has spread from many areas of SouthEast Asia, namely India, and has reached Egypt. The disease has affected many people and places, including Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/AndersonBubonicPlague2.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;The Plague Strikes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people have come down with the disease, and many have been admitted to hospitals. Deaths have also been
associated with this deadly disease. The disease has turned into an epidemic since it once again arose from the depths of ancient times. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmvh.org/article/the-history-of-plague-part-1-the-three-great-pandemics/&quot;&gt;JMVH&lt;/a&gt;, this new plague, still spread from rats and rat fleas, has taken over all parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it has reached Egypt and Alexandria and has no signs of stopping anytime soon. Death rates are high for the disease, and in some cities without hospitals many people are at risk. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/plague/history/&quot;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt; has reported that people should stay away from many of the rats infecting cities, because the cause of the disease is unknown as of yet. Many people die each day as reported in the newspapers, and more are being committed into hospitals at the same time. Many hope that the death rates of the plague decrease over time, but for many people whose family members have already been infected have little hope for the future. Some talk about vaccines and ways to stop the disease, but we have not received any of it yet because people are still dying. Many people in the areas affected by the plague cannot afford to find help, so in some cases, they are left to die on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/AndersonBubonicPlague2.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Death on the Street&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Bubonic Plague" />
			
				<category term="Egypt" />
			

			<published>2017-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Petersen-Gum-Blog/</id>
			<title>The Gum Trade</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Petersen-Gum-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Gum Trade" />
			<updated>2017-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JustinPetersen</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Yesterday gums up today</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Petersen-Gum-Blog/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;gum-in-1906&quot;&gt;Gum in 1906&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something I use every day I hardly think about the origins of it. I never considered the history of gum, but when I saw the article about the gum trade on Wednesday July 11th 1906 it made me think about how long people have been chewing gum. It’s quite interesting to think about. I am an avid gum chewer, so to think about the people that have been in my position a hundred years ago makes me feel quite small in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gum-trading&quot;&gt;Gum Trading?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Egypt in 1906 was a major distributor of gum. They exported thousands of cantars of gum, for a decent profit, considering they apparently are a major distributor of the product. However, up to the end of June 1906, their crop yield was only half of what it was around that time the year before. This probably ended up being a severe loss in profit, but Egypt had plenty of money from other exports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-was-gum-actually-used-for&quot;&gt;What was gum actually used for?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also began to wonder if gum was actually used for chewing. Could it have been used for other purposes like so many things that existed hundreds of years ago. Was it used to hold something together? Was it used to stop leakages? Maybe it is used just as it is today, just as a way to keep your breath smelling fresh all day, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-answer&quot;&gt;The Answer…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon further inspection the use of gum was not at all what it is used for today. I found out that “Arabic Gum” was used primarily as a food stabilizer. However, it was also used in traditional lithography, it was used in printing, paint production, glue and even cosmetics. Obviously this means that Gum in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is not the same as the gum sitting in my pocket in 2017. I discovered that substitutes for chewing gum had been invented since the Ancient Greeks, however that was just tree bark. So, overall, gum as referred to in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is quite different from the gum of today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="gum" />
			

			<published>2017-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>