<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
	<updated>2017-01-03T22:47:55-05:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Will Hanley</name>
			
			
				<email>whanley@fsu.edu</email>
			
			
				<uri>http://nationality-history.info/</uri>
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.2">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/</id>
			<title>A Reflection on the Tech</title>
			<link href="/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Reflection on the Tech" />
			<updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>AlexanderAmorello</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Pressing Ctrl+S every once and while is good decision. Trust me </summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/">&lt;p&gt;I feel like this second blog post is going to saturated with negatives, so I’ll try to keep mine a little brighter by starting with the fact that this initially pain-staking process has really grown on me. At first it was a total chore, slowly trouble shooting every single issue that I had with the multiple programs I had no familiarity with (Oxygen, ABBYY Finereader, and Github), wishing that my advisor would’ve warned better beforehand of such things and hoping that I would have a free weekend again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after about 3 solid weeks of working, something clicked. I started enjoying this previously arduous work. The trouble-shooting became enjoyable, as every issue came to me as an interesting puzzle rather than a pace-breaking wall. Also, the whole philosophy behind this encoding became much clearer to me, and in a way, inspired me to take special care when it came to encoding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things on the tech side that I believe led me to enjoying this process more were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Having a larger monitor to work on: I like having all the information I need to encode in view all at once, it helps me keep things in order and it just keeps things more accurate. Having a monitor that is larger than a standard 13-15-17 in laptop screen really helped me. I was able to pull up boilerplates, have oxygen open, and have a reference scanned image open all in sizes that I could view easily. This expedited the process greatly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Using a mouse: After trying to encode and OCR on my Surface and comparing it to my work on my desktop, I noticed a night and day difference in quality of pages and general frustration. The mouse allows you to have more exact control of your cursor and gives a less clunky access to your keyboard whilst moving your cursor between multiple points quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and some other technical mishaps/advice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Make sure you take the highest quality scans of your microfilm as possible: Because I was foolish and decided to separate my scanning sessions into different days, I ended up getting two different qualities of scans. This made OCR’ing extremely frustrating as it made some pages correctable in about 20 minutes and other pages taking over an hour and a half. In short, SCAN HIGHEST DPI POSSIBLE AND MAKE SURE THE SCANNER GLASS DOES NOT HAVE EXCESSIVE SMUDGING.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Always press Ctrl+S or “Save” after every page you finish in your issues: It’s been about 3 times that I’ve been so caught up in encoding that I forget to save for a few pages. Inevitably my computer updates or Oxygen crashes, and all that work is lost, leading to one too many instances of my palm colliding with my forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml&quot;&gt;TEI webpage&lt;/a&gt; should be considered the holy text of this class. It is referenced by Dr. Hanley, and simple guides are available on dig-eg-gaz. But if you need find anything specific, get spiritual and make a journey into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical" />
			
			
				<category term="premature aging" />
			
				<category term="keyboard smashing rage" />
			
				<category term="stress eating" />
			
				<category term="OCR" />
			
				<category term="Oxygen" />
			
				<category term="Lack of Oxygen" />
			

			<published>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/</id>
			<title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Higher Learning through the Newspaper" />
			<updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>AlexanderAmorello</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Would you apply to a Secondary Institution because of advertisement in the newspaper?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/">&lt;p&gt;Within a every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an “English School”. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the “Cheap Pre-paid advertisement” column on Page 5’s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the “English School, Nicosia” advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history&quot; title=&quot;Nicosia English School Official History Page&quot;&gt;notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus&quot;&gt;Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it’s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it’s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Nicosia_school.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though during this time secondary education wasn’t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="Education" />
			
				<category term="Berlitz" />
			
				<category term="Language" />
			
				<category term="1900s" />
			

			<published>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/curiosities/Chack-On-blogpost1/</id>
			<title>Curiosity on The powers of The World</title>
			<link href="/curiosities/Chack-On-blogpost1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curiosity on The powers of The World" />
			<updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>josephchackon &lt;!--- all one word ---&gt;</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The newspaper covers an array of subjects. But the armies, admirals and leaders general take over the page.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/curiosities/Chack-On-blogpost1/">&lt;p&gt;The people of the Egypt or the Egyptian Gazette cover a broad range of topics covering day to day functions that benefit the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it has also been a hub for expressing foreign or neighboring military powers and the actions they are making.
 An interesting part of nearly all of the third pages in my week of the newspaper have featured either government or military leaders and their most up to date business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example would be on the third page of June 9 issue where topics covered a British submarine sinking and the death of a prince. In comparison to the modern world where such information is a simple tap or click away this was most likely the quickest and cheapest way to stay informed about the powers that governed their world. Especially since everyday was a new paper it’s almost safe to say that it was close to accurate to determine where ships are head or are currently located. Especially if such a power was nearby knowing about the government plans was also necessary. Businesses relied on the paper but the interesting things that were going on in the paper was always foreign relations and the day to day habits of those with influence. Government rules or maybe some command was sent out in order to deal with an issue so its safe to say the people relied on the government to solve certain issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="curiosities" />
			
			
				<category term="military" />
			

			<published>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20questions/Medical-Miracles/</id>
			<title>Medical Miracles</title>
			<link href="/serial%20questions/Medical-Miracles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medical Miracles" />
			<updated>2016-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>ValerieCurcio &lt;!--- all one word ---&gt;</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Do these magical pills really work?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20questions/Medical-Miracles/">&lt;p&gt;The one topic throughout this whole newspaper that consistently grabbed my
attention and amazed me time and time again was the unbelievable stories
of medical miracles happening.  The feature that really caught my attention was
from Doan’s Backache Kidney Pills apparently saving a man from being bed ridden
his whole life.  This claim was so shocking to me because I am familiar with this
brand, my dad takes it for his minor back pains he gets while at work or if he
over does it at the gym.  I was baffled to see this huge of a success story.
Were the ingredients of a higher potency?  Could medicine really have been this
advanced over a century ago? People were being cured from severe medical
ailments, by a box of pills from the drugstore.  Conditions confining them to
their beds and hindering them from work and everyday life, were suddenly gone.
My serial question is how successful really were these pills? I will be
researching how many cases of medical success resulted from the Doan’s Backache
Kidney Pills in particular over the course of this year.  I will also go into
further studies of the proclaimed brand and gain more historical and background
knowledge of its origins and the pill’s chemical makeup.  I hope to conclude
how successful of a brand this really was and determine if it was as miraculous
as the people of Egypt claim.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial questions" />
			
			
				<category term="medicine" />
			
				<category term="pills" />
			
				<category term="cures" />
			

			<published>2016-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20questions/Esteve-Counting/</id>
			<title>Counting Things</title>
			<link href="/serial%20questions/Esteve-Counting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Counting Things" />
			<updated>2016-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>JustinEsteve &lt;!--- all one word ---&gt;</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>What kinds of different ways can I count things?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20questions/Esteve-Counting/">&lt;p&gt;As I began thinking about what type of serial question I was interested in, I initially began focusing on advertisements. Specifically, I wanted to count the number of ads in the newspaper and make a graph using my results. However, as I began using different queries, I realized that just counting advertisements was not really interesting. Because of this, I began counting other things. I started manipulating my queries in order to count in different ways. At the moment, I can count specific words throughout the paper. I can count divs, heads, and paragraphs. As I focus on this serial question, I will find different queries for counting. I wish to explore how counting in XPath queries can reveal different types of information in the newspaper. I plan on using counting queries to manipulate information in the newspaper and then coming up with conclusions based on those queries. This will also be a great tool for current and future students to better understand counting in Oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to counting things, I will make a series of graphs to go along with my queries. Obviously, everyone in the class is at different stages of completing their weeks. Because of this, I will find a way to somewhat determine how reliable everyone’s data is. The completion of Page One can be found by looking at the number of divs. For my purposes, I want a better overall picture. If I can find a way to count words or paragraphs, I will be much happier with the results. With that goal in mind, I have been playing with string queries. If I can find a way to see which weeks are more accurate, I can make some solid conclusions based on the data that I find.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial questions" />
			
			
				<category term="counting" />
			
				<category term="querying" />
			

			<published>2016-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/</id>
			<title>Numerical Nonsense</title>
			<link href="/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Numerical Nonsense" />
			<updated>2016-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>ValerieCurcio &lt;!--- all one word ---&gt;</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A-B-C  1-2..is that a 3 or an 8?</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered many problems during the course of this class.  From
my flash drive, containing all of my microfilm scans becoming corrupted to
running out of trial time on just about every application we needed.  But the one
thing that stands above all else, is translating the minuscule blurred text,
mainly numerical values included in the financial tables.  I found the OCR
converter to be quite useless, words came out a jumbled mess and often
everything was out of order.  I ended up retyping many portions of the pages
manually, this was until I discovered stitching process and this made things a
bit easier for me.  From that point forward, I mainly just had problems
deciphering numbers and inputing them all from scratch into the templates.  The
numbers on the newspaper were very hard to make out especially the fractional
values, I could almost never distinguish what they were, and maybe if I had
scanned with more brightness or focus it would have helped but for the most
part, I think it was poor formatting of the newspaper itself.  I had to just gave
it my best guess for a majority of the pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the work was very tedious and stressful at times, definitely not for the
faint of heart.  But nothing was more rewarding than successfully accomplishing
my xml files.  Being able to read them back with ease and finally enjoy some of
the bizarre stories during this time period was very enlightening and often
very funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical" />
			
			
				<category term="tag" />
			

			<published>2016-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20question/summa-serial/</id>
			<title>An Analysis of the Activities of Three Major Cities in 1905</title>
			<link href="/serial%20question/summa-serial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Analysis of the Activities of Three Major Cities in 1905" />
			<updated>2016-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>CelitaSumma</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Happenings in London, Paris, and St. Petersburg</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20question/summa-serial/">&lt;p&gt;For my serial question, I plan to ask the question “What topics are discussed in the international section of the Egyptian Gazette and how do these topics differ based on location?” In order to query this, I will use an XPath command to search the datelines in the international section. All occurrences will then return for my desired city names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three cities I have chosen to analyze are Paris, France, London, England, and St. Petersburg, Russia. For each dateline that returns with one of those cities, I will classify the news blurb in a category and compile three pie charts- one for each city. These pie charts, when placed side-by-side, will not only provide viewers with an idea of the most frequently discussed topics and occurrences in each city, but will also provide a comparison between the cities. Viewers will be able to see which topics are most-discussed in one city and compare that topic to another. When tied in with the world events that were occurring, this should come together cohesively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important research to conduct because it will hopefully shed some light onto what was most important to people and how that importance varied from city to city.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial question" />
			
			
				<category term="questions" />
			
				<category term="London" />
			
				<category term="Paris" />
			
				<category term="St. Petersburg" />
			

			<published>2016-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20question/cooper-serial/</id>
			<title>Who is the fastest horse in Alexandria?</title>
			<link href="/serial%20question/cooper-serial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who is the fastest horse in Alexandria?" />
			<updated>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>MatthewCooper</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>My topic for the final portion of the class</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20question/cooper-serial/">&lt;p&gt;For my serial question for this course, I would like to find out who the fastest horse in all of Alexandria during the year of 1905. The topic sparked my interest while I was coding the xml for my page threes. I am fascinated by sports and I noticed that there were reoccurring articles regarding horse racing and bets taking place around the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manner in which I plan to go about doing my analysis for my final project is querying the entirety of the Gazette for keywords like “horse” and “race” and “odds”. This will help me find what I am looking for in order to compile data to see who the most victorious race horse was. It would be very interesting to find the Secretariat of the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, I will not run into any other problems for the remainder of this troublesome course. It has been quite difficult to complete basically every single portion of the work, and I am glad to be nearing completion of the class.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="Serial Question" />
			
			

			<published>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/serial%20questions/Crawford-Serial-Question/</id>
			<title>Capital Market Integration</title>
			<link href="/serial%20questions/Crawford-Serial-Question/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Capital Market Integration" />
			<updated>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>williamcrawford</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Exploring trans-oceanic connections in turn-of-the-century capital markets</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/serial%20questions/Crawford-Serial-Question/">&lt;p&gt;For my serial question, I am interested in examining the behavior of asset prices in the local financial market. I entered this class with the prior knowledge that there was a banking crisis in Alexandria in 1907 that is said to be driven by excessive speculation in the local real estate market on the local level, but which is said by other economic courses to have found its impetus in a global financial crisis that was caused the 1906 earthquake in San Francisco. The explanation is that the excessive stress put on the financial system by numerous simultaneous insurance payouts. The implication of this explanation is that international capital markets were sufficiently integrated to allow localized shocks to affect to spread globally. But was this the case? And if so, just how integrated were these capital markets in the age before the instantaneous flows of digital information that are said to be the justification for assumptions of perfect capital mobility. To attempt to quantitatively answer this question, I will draw upon the theories of interest rate parity. I will provide a longer and more thorough explanation of this in my final project, but to put it simply, it’s the idea than in a world of perfect information and capital mobility, prices for identical assets will be equal in different markets, removing the potential for arbitrage. To tie this to ideas of capital market integration, the magnitude and persistence of prices differentials would suggest the degree and speed to which various international financial markets react to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, I hope to pull price information for a particular asset over the course of the year, and compare it the prices for the same asset in the markets in both New York and London. I will then analyze and attempt to draw conclusions from the resulting data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="serial questions" />
			
			
				<category term="trade" />
			

			<published>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/</id>
			<title>XML encoding in Finereader</title>
			<link href="/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="XML encoding in Finereader" />
			<updated>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>williamcrawford</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Seeing through the noise</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/">&lt;p&gt;Balancing a logical, accessible, and user friendly xml-encodation of the Egyptian Gazette with preserving its historical visual format is a delicate enterprise. I initially tried to do this with a plaintext editor, and later directly within the Oxygen program itself. I found myself constantly switching between windows on my computer, going back and forth and then back again between the image of the page and the xml-in-progress. By chance, I had to go and re-OCR a page three about a month into the class, and discovered something that greatly decreased the time it took me to structure a page with XML tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By placing individual text boxes over individual paragraphs on the page, Finereader would output the OCRed text in a form that was sectionally pre-divided within the plain-text-viewer. By easily distinguishing the divisions with physical space, it allowed me to rapidly go through and paste repetitive structural elements. Additionally, the image of the page (that would automatically relocate to the plain text’s location when I selected it) that was always visible aided me in determining how exactly to structure the divisions to both best maintain the paper�s original appearance and take advantage of the power of XML coding to analyze it. I then used Oxygen to functionally check and edit the code.  Combined, I found that these factors greatly reduced the amount of time it took me to structurally code the text.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="technical issues" />
			
			
				<category term="shortcuts" />
			

			<published>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>