<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Fires in 1905</title>
				<link>/serial/Fling-Serial-Question/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In my week of the Gazette I came across a Ship that caught
on fire. This report was found on page 3 of November 25, 1905.
The ship was full of cotton and rice when it was
set aflame. Flames were not visible but smoke was pouring
out from the vessel. The smoke calmed due to incessant pumping
for about 2 hours. But soon after the ship fire seemed to be
controlled, the smoke bursted forth again.
2 hours later, it was decided that the ship was to be put
ashore, on the bank in hopes that the hold would fill with
water to subdue the fire. This did the trick and finally
calmed the fire upon the ship.
Oddly, the cause of the fire is reported as,
“unknown.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section of the newspaper seems to report the most
severe of fires. I am curious, as to what the other weeks of the
Egyptian Gazette will have to offer about such fires. My serial
question for the 1905 Egyptian Gazette will be: How often did
the Egyptian Gazette report Fires in 1905? I will also be researching
why these fires occurred. In this instance, the cause of the Fire is
known. I wonder if the Gazette often list the cause to these fires
as known.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial/Fling-Serial-Question/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Serial Analysis of Deaths in Alexandria in 1905</title>
				<link>/questions/deaths/causes/maps/summa-serial/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For my serial question, I would like to explore all of the deaths in
Alexandria that occurred during the year 1905. Once I have collected
all of the articles and blurbs that mention deaths in the Egyptian
Gazette, I will conduct further analysis by assigning specific locations
to those deaths that provide such information. Then, I will be able to
use these locations to create a map of deaths throughout the city. In
order to ensure a comprehensive analysis, if not enough deaths are tagged
with a specific location, I will also create a pie chart showing the
distribution of cause of death. If enough locations are tagged in the
paper, I will color code the causes of death before plotting them on the
map, which should help to give a general overview of which causes of
death are relevant in certain parts of the city, or if any correlation
exists at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an important analysis to conduct because it should hopefully
shed some light on the reasons for death, ages of death, and locations
of death throughout Alexandria. By delving into this topic, I hope to
answer the question “How did people die in Alexandria in 1905?” and draw
parallels to the causes of death now and how the two differ.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/questions/deaths/causes/maps/summa-serial/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical</title>
				<link>/technical/rymer-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A large portion of this class involves using completely new technologies and applying them to very difficult media.  While technologies such as github, OCR, and
XML weren’t terribly hard to learn, the application of them for the first time definitely led me to some technical errors that had to be sorted out.  These technical errors
included poor text recognition that left much of the text unusable, difficult to obtain XML software, and incorrect XML tagging.  The first of these errors can be attributed
to poor condition of century old documents.  While I was able to focus the microfilm reader very well, many portions of these documents had text that was copied slightly on
top of itself and occasionally with weak ink.  This led to problems such as columns being mixed together, text that didn’t go through OCR at all, and many errors overall.
Another technical error I faced was incorrect XML tagging.  After I made all the divs in a page cascade perfectly, I found out that I had tagged headers and subheaders using
the wrong tags, which was solved using find and replace and also a lot of rearranging of the XML.  Overall, I was able to understand these new technologies fairly smoothly,
and I was able to determine the cause of a few technical errors that came up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/rymer-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cotton Exports</title>
				<link>/serial%20questions/grieco-cotton-serial-question/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For my serial question, I will be examining the trends in cotton exports to different countries using the monthly “Coton” table included in the financial section of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Specifically, I will be looking to see whether there are any variations in export volume (measured in bales) due to changes in season, significant domestic and international historical events, or any other major influences of demand. Particularly, this serial question gives me the unique opportunity to examine how complex international relationships at the turn of the century between Great Britain and other states might have trickled down to affect more localized factors, such as cotton exportation from one of its most valued colonies. I believe this questions reflects the spirit of one of the principal goals of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20questions/grieco-cotton-serial-question/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Serial Question</title>
				<link>/serial%20question/evanoff-serial/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My serial question is stemming from a series of passages I read in my issue.
There seems to be a massacre of the Jewish population in Russia. I found this
to be interesting because this is decades prior to World War II, where there
was mass homicide of the Jews in Europe. I would like to explore how this built
up throughout the year and what reports are reaching Egypt. They are reporting
mass killings but seem to remain an objective third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to say that history has a way of repeating itself. It interests
me that there was mass homicide of the Jewish population 30 years prior to the
most infamous (dare I say successful) murder of millions of Jews. I intend to
explore this topic and the history of conflict Europeans had with the Jewish
population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20question/evanoff-serial/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Death in Alexandria 1905</title>
				<link>/curiosities/evanoff-curiosity/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 1905 Alexandria on my third pages I have noticed a lot of deaths being
reported in the newspaper. There was a child killed by a horse in an accident
and it received approximately 3 lines of text with little to no commentary.
When the Grand Mufti died he had almost an entire column in every single page
of the newspaper. They made updates on the family and commented on his well
being as well as his wishes for the future and memories of the past. It is
so sad to see in this paper how little the newspapers covered tragedies like
children dying and they covered an older man who had been dying for a while so
heavily. I understand having to put the Grand Mufti in the spotlight since
he was the leader of the country, however it is quite the travesty to see
people being disregarded publicly. They need to give them the respect they
deserve, or just not mention it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/evanoff-curiosity/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technology Troubles</title>
				<link>/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks of this semester I was completely dedicated to toiling for hours in order to receive an “A” in this class. I would stay up until midnight finishing editing text that was OCRd making sure that no detail was overlooked. I would spend hours working on this editing only to go back to it and find that all of my hard work had either disappeared or been undone and not for lack of saving. When I started working with Oxygen, I would find that a file I had just started coding the previous night could not be found when I went to open and edit it the next day. This setback has been a source of major frustration for obvious reasons. I don’t know whether this unfortunate series of events is occurring because of some delayed karma or because I have the dreaded apple computer but it has caused me to become lazy with the workload. That being said, I have prayed to the computer gods to fix my issues so I can save my grade and it seems to have worked so far. In the wake of my realization about how quickly the semester is coming to an end I have kicked back into gear and have decided to push through any and all technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Deadly Dates</title>
				<link>/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You love your family but there’s always those cousins that just annoy you so much that sometimes you just want to feed them some poisoned dates so you don’t have to deal with them anymore. Well that’s precisely what one man of Makhadoora village did to his cousins in May of 1905. This nameless man injected compressed dates with enough of a deadly poison to kill those who ate it. He then gave these deadly fruits to five of his cousins, two men and three women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three women ate the dates and “expired in great agony.” Now if you are not a psychopath, you might be confused as to why this man decided to off his cousins and especially in such a cruel and painful way. Did they inherit a large sum of money from grandma while the killer only received the nice china? Did they eat all of the stuffing at Thanksgiving when they knew it was his favorite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to the lack of information provided about a motive or even a name for the killer, the world may never know. One thing that is known however, is that this event did cause “considerable excitement” throughout the neighborhood due to the simple fact that it was a murder as opposed to an accidental date poisoning. In my opinion, this fact implies that the neighborhood in Keneh where the murders took place was not used to this violence which might mean that it was a fairly well-off neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that the motive could involve money? It could certainly be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Break</title>
				<link>/technical/Crespo-Break/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s almost the end of the semester and I am still on the second blog post, wow. At the beginning of the semester I had a big issue, my brand-new MacBook stopped working. At first they believed my trackpad and keyboard were not working because of a virus on my computer, they gave it back after deleting the virus and it went back to not working, after that I took it back and they worked on it for another week and believed they had fixed the problem, I got it back and a few days later I was still on the same page. The Apple technicians at the bookstore got to know my name very well as I had to keep going back. In the end my MacBook took about a month to get fully repaired, they ended up having to replace the whole keyboard, so obviously, I fell behind. Once I got it back I began to work deliberately on the material, although it is not difficult work, I would still find myself spending hours in front of my computer without much progress. So much correcting, so many things to fill in, plus handling four other classes at the same time, so stressful. Cisdem OCR helped me so much more than the ABBYY OCR, it could detect the print much more precisely which made the process a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Crespo-Break/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical Issues</title>
				<link>/technical/vincent-technical-post/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During my journey in IFS2116, I have faced many issues. Some of the issues were easily fixed, some were hard to fix, and some are just plain impossible to fix. My first issue came along the first or second week of class
when I tried scanning my pages. The computers did not work and then I had to rescan the majority of my page threes.
The journey is long and tedious and very very time consuming. Another issue I faced was the bad quality of image in general. Many of my images
had missing words, blurred words, or a mixture of both. Some of the issues even had missing spots in the paper that left me clueless to what belonged in those spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another technical issue I came across was the ads. A lot of the ads had very tiny bold font that was very difficult to read
and faded as the ad continued down the page. Though there were many difficulties, I do have to say that I learned a great deal from these problems.
These technical issues has led me to believe that nothing is perfect and it is those little imperfections that make the Egyptian Gazette Newspaper so beautiful.
We all must understand that these pages have been passed on for over 50 years and nothing that old is perfect. The amazing thing is how researchers, like ourselves, go about solving these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/vincent-technical-post/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
