<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical</title>
				<link>/technical/rymer-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A large portion of this class involves using completely new technologies and applying them to very difficult media.  While technologies such as github, OCR, and
XML weren’t terribly hard to learn, the application of them for the first time definitely led me to some technical errors that had to be sorted out.  These technical errors
included poor text recognition that left much of the text unusable, difficult to obtain XML software, and incorrect XML tagging.  The first of these errors can be attributed
to poor condition of century old documents.  While I was able to focus the microfilm reader very well, many portions of these documents had text that was copied slightly on
top of itself and occasionally with weak ink.  This led to problems such as columns being mixed together, text that didn’t go through OCR at all, and many errors overall.
Another technical error I faced was incorrect XML tagging.  After I made all the divs in a page cascade perfectly, I found out that I had tagged headers and subheaders using
the wrong tags, which was solved using find and replace and also a lot of rearranging of the XML.  Overall, I was able to understand these new technologies fairly smoothly,
and I was able to determine the cause of a few technical errors that came up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/rymer-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Discussion of Converting Text</title>
				<link>/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My biggest problem with the entire process has been with the OCR process. Perhaps due to poor original scans, or perhaps due to poor images
from the source, I have had serious problems with my OCR coming out correctly. Unfortunately, I’ve had to manually type every page and it has
caused me countless headaches and more than one mental breakdown. Luckily, things got a bit smoother after finishing all my page 3’s. That being
said, I’m still working extremely hard at catching up and finishing what I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Exploring Expeditions</title>
				<link>/serial%20questions/Taylor-blog-post-3/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Originally, I thought that my serial question was going to focus on missing persons and examine the amount of information provided for each particular circumstance. However, as I began to try to develop a query for that topic, I had difficulty finding much data other than what I had seen in my issue. So, I began to explore new ideas. I found myself still interested in the stories concerning specific people and began to investigate random names. I eventually found that there were multiple accounts in multiple issues tracking the movement of explorers. With this, I began to wonder about the most common reasons and locations for expeditions reported in the 1905 Egyptian Gazette. I developed a simple query to find information relating to my question by searching for items containing the word “expedition.” This brought back quite a few results. My hope is that the information gathered from these results will provide some insight into the “who, what, and why” of the expeditions reported in the paper. I also hope to discover how many of these were “successful” and what determined them to be so. I anticipate some trends in location and perhaps even in the reasons for traveling. For the final analysis, I believe that a map will be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20questions/Taylor-blog-post-3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Sad Englishman</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Ragland-A-sad-englishman/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A rather unfortunate English soldier was captured by an employee of a Turkish tobacco company who sent one of his ears to the Consul at Monastir, ordering a ransom be paid for him.  Interestingly enough, this tobacco company is still around today–in a sense.  The company was the Ottoman Empire’s largest foreign investment.  It was called “Tekel” in 1825, but is actually still called “Regie” in Lebanon.  I found it interesting that the company selling Lebanese tobacco is the same company which cut off an English soldier’s ear way back in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Ragland-A-sad-englishman/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Enteric Fever</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Eugenio-entericfever/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;While reading through the Egyptian Gazette issues I was assigned, I came across an article that has to do with Enteric Fever. This article intrigued me because I was not familiar with the disease. After reading through the article it sparked my interest and I began to look up what this disease was. I found out that Enteric Fever is also known as Typhoid Fever. This illness is associated with Salmonella typhi bacteria. After reading more about it I realized that Typhoid is caused by bacteria that is similar to Salmonella. This article discusses how it is important to carry out preventative methods for this disease in the army. It then goes on to explain that the health efficiency of the Army has been increased by a lot. They talk about how they encourage men in the army to have better hygiene in hopes for better overall health. I think this is interesting because the article discusses the different types of methods they use to prevent the disease, such as boiling drinking water. It is interesting to see the medical advances for this time compared to current time. Enteric is such a big deal during this time and the prevention of the disease is so important, however as of now I had not even recognized this disease until I read further into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Eugenio-entericfever/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Difficulties with Converting images into XML</title>
				<link>/technical/Eugenio-Converting-Difficulties/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest difficulty I have encountered is converting my Egyptian Gazette images into the XML format. After scanning my issues of the Egyptian Gazette I then used the Cisdem PDFConverterOCR to convert my images into text files. After doing this I noticed many errors within my text file and it took me hours to edit one page, sometimes causing me to retype the entire page. Most of my text file would be random letters or symbols that were impossible to decipher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After retyping many pages I learned about rescanning photos and the stitching process. I then used this method to rescan my image files and as for the Cisdem converter this made the images more clear and the text came out more fluent but there were still errors but not nearly as much as before. Due to the several errors I have in my text files it has slowed down the entire process for me. I believe I have spent most of my time working on fixing the text. Once moving past this portion I was able to get into more interesting things and was able to add tags and organize my XML files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe if I had understood the stitching process sooner I would have saved myself hours and would not have had to retype pages entirely. However, once I progressed past this portion of the work I noticed that ad pages were much easier and took less time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Eugenio-Converting-Difficulties/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Diseases of Egypt in 1905</title>
				<link>/serial%20question/Cyr-Serial-Question/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this blog post is to investigate a serial question within the Egyptian Gazette. The serial question should
discuss a pattern of information that is found throughout the year. My question of interest surrounds various diseases that were
present in Egypt in the year of 1905, and perhaps a more narrow focus can then be geared toward the
most prevalent disease found in this area at this time. So the serial question(s) could be, “What kind of diseases were prevalent in Egypt
during this time-period? Does any one disease stand out in particular?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find this information, a search of other classmates’ work on the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; will be conducted in order
to find as much information possible on the diseases presented by this newspaper. It is important to note
that due to space and limited knowledge of the time, many diseases may not have been reported to, or
expressed by, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Information is also limited to how well students have transferred the digitized
newspaper to .xml in Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/PlagueSnippet.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I hope to achieve with my serial question?:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I would like to have a solid amount of information about diseases in Egypt within the time period of 1905. In order to
obtain this information, the cumulative work of other students will need to be gathered within the course content and gleaned over.
I would like to then gather this information and present it in a visual way for others to easily understand. Information within a visual
graph should show people what diseases are prevalent in this area, at this time and observers should be able to determine easily which
diseases were most prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some hiccups in the way. Some work done on the website may not have been coded properly, or it may have been coded in different
ways which return different results during a search. This creates a problem when using the search function XPath Query. This query searches
the cumulative work of all students in regards to the entire year of 1905, within the Egyptian Gazette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/search_term1.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above image shows many results for various search terms. Searching for diseases within the Egyptian Gazette requires multiple
search terms. For instance, a search of “disease” may yield different results compared to “diseases”. Another issue is sifting through
information that is not relevant to disease: a search of the term “sick” may return two results 1) “I am sick of these hot summers,” or 2) “I
have a friend that is sick from the flu.” These two results clearly have different uses of the word and as a result, requires the observing
student to read each item in question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20question/Cyr-Serial-Question/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dead Doggies</title>
				<link>/serial%20questions/Sain-Serial-Discovery/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;dogs-sentenced-to-death&quot;&gt;Dogs Sentenced to Death&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some of the issues, under the “Local and General” section of the paper, there are sometimes small articles labeled “Stray and Ownerless Dogs,” which is a report of the dogs that have been found that day and where there were discovered. The snippets also always say that the dogs are to be poisoned if not collected. I find this section of the newspaper interesting because it is the announcement of very miniscule news. I find the local and general portion important because it shows the minor details that occur in the day-to-day lives of the citizens of Alexandria. It’s interesting to compare the way animals are talked about in 1905 as compared to now. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.americanhumane.org/about-us/history/&quot;&gt;In 1905 animals&lt;/a&gt; were viewed mostly as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=kn9xAAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA214&amp;amp;lpg=PA214&amp;amp;dq=treatment+of+animals+in+1905&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=bOPeHYezYT&amp;amp;sig=Ew1RbTvDBxKcu8IgZF0b9YwgfZ4&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi8v7TIl8rQAhUBEGMKHc73A4gQ6AEIJzAC#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=treatment%20of%20animals%20in%201905&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;agricultural resource&lt;/a&gt; rather than house pets, like how we use them now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/two-dog-pic.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Two Dogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs were not valued as greatly as they are now. In 1905, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=2189AQAAMAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA609&amp;amp;lpg=PA609&amp;amp;dq=why+were+dogs+poisoned+by+police+1905&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=f2oUZReMBt&amp;amp;sig=zgJ_Y7hHagKLWJyaSBzxSvfPVZA&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiDvPzgmcrQAhVCqFQKHQQJAQ8Q6AEINDAE#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=poisoned%20dogs&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;the poisoning (and drowning)&lt;/a&gt; of dogs was common and is expected to happen if dogs are found stray and are not claimed. This section may be useful because people could potentially have their animals returned to them, although the declaration of their poisoning is slightly depressing, it is fascinating that it is mentioned in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/picasso-dog.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Picasso Dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20questions/Sain-Serial-Discovery/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Egyptian Gazette Structural Issues</title>
				<link>/technical/Esteve-EgyptianGazetteStructuralIssues/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During my week of the Egyptian Gazette, I have several page sevens that are unlike the other pages. These pages focus on travel and mostly have hotel advertisements. However, they also contain commentary about the best way to travel to different places and the differences in climate between the two. This commentary is split between all six columns of the newspaper. There are some advertisements (see below) that are similar in that they take up two columns. However, I have no idea how to encode these page sevens in order to reflect the structure of the newspaper. Up till now, I have just grouped the commentary in one div. If I encoded the page sevens by columns, I would get six random groups of text. Obviously, this would cause a great deal of confusion unless there was a way to connect the text in each column together. A tag that connects the text together might work, but this issue is definitely one worth exploring as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/1905-12-11-p8-Structure.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;advertisements&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Esteve-EgyptianGazetteStructuralIssues/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>OCR Woes</title>
				<link>/technical/grieco-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For my technical reflection, I have decided to discuss my experiences with the
OCR software, simply because it was easily the most time-consuming and tedious
portion of the technical aspects of this class. Since I have a Mac laptop, I
used the Cisdem OCR software rather than ABBY Finereader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I would like to say is the accuracy with which it translates
the text is quite disappointing. I would estimate that at MOST 60% of the
original text was transcribed to my text editor properly, and even more
frustrating was that specific letters were nearly almost incorrectly written,
for instance the letter “e” for the entirety of the respective pages was often
incorrectly recorded as the letter “a”, and vice versa. Furthermore,
spell-checking entire pages written in French was both lengthy and difficult,
particularly when I could not read some of the words and could not use context
clues to figure out what they were supposed to say (because I do not speak
French). At a certain point I had to simply accept that my XML pages were simply
going to be filled with egregious errors and a certain level of accuracy was
impossible to achieve (much to the chagrin of my mild OCD, but hey it was a
learning experience in patience and Zen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was not a fan of the OCR software. It was most likely faster than
manually transcribing entire pages of the newspaper, but it was nonetheless
aggravating and stressful. Rant over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/grieco-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
