<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Result of hashish</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Barbosa-Hashish/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A husband bought some hashish paste, which, after some research, is a recreational drug that has the same active ingredients as marijuana. He had a dose and made the mistake of giving his wife the rest. After she kept tasting it, she saw a fire and began to scream. Her husband rushed towards her and called the police because of the huge fire they saw. When the police arrived, there was no fire and the couple thought that a small roof lamp was the huge fire. I am curious as to whether the couple got punished for taking any form of marijuana and what any other effects happened because of the event. Did friends, family, neighbors, and co-workers make fun of them for such an event? How is marijuana use seen in society back then? Also, was marijuana common or illegal back then. Were laws on drugs strict back then? Another thing I am curious about is just how much did they take to somehow imagine a fire from a lamp. Was their event used as an example against drug use? Of course this event managed to make it into the newspaper so does that mean that it became viral over the town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Barbosa-Hashish/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Reflection on the Tech</title>
				<link>/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like this second blog post is going to saturated with negatives, so I’ll try to keep mine a little brighter by starting with the fact that this initially pain-staking process has really grown on me. At first it was a total chore, slowly trouble shooting every single issue that I had with the multiple programs I had no familiarity with (Oxygen, ABBYY Finereader, and Github), wishing that my advisor would’ve warned better beforehand of such things and hoping that I would have a free weekend again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after about 3 solid weeks of working, something clicked. I started enjoying this previously arduous work. The trouble-shooting became enjoyable, as every issue came to me as an interesting puzzle rather than a pace-breaking wall. Also, the whole philosophy behind this encoding became much clearer to me, and in a way, inspired me to take special care when it came to encoding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things on the tech side that I believe led me to enjoying this process more were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Having a larger monitor to work on: I like having all the information I need to encode in view all at once, it helps me keep things in order and it just keeps things more accurate. Having a monitor that is larger than a standard 13-15-17 in laptop screen really helped me. I was able to pull up boilerplates, have oxygen open, and have a reference scanned image open all in sizes that I could view easily. This expedited the process greatly&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using a mouse: After trying to encode and OCR on my Surface and comparing it to my work on my desktop, I noticed a night and day difference in quality of pages and general frustration. The mouse allows you to have more exact control of your cursor and gives a less clunky access to your keyboard whilst moving your cursor between multiple points quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and some other technical mishaps/advice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you take the highest quality scans of your microfilm as possible: Because I was foolish and decided to separate my scanning sessions into different days, I ended up getting two different qualities of scans. This made OCR’ing extremely frustrating as it made some pages correctable in about 20 minutes and other pages taking over an hour and a half. In short, SCAN HIGHEST DPI POSSIBLE AND MAKE SURE THE SCANNER GLASS DOES NOT HAVE EXCESSIVE SMUDGING.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always press Ctrl+S or “Save” after every page you finish in your issues: It’s been about 3 times that I’ve been so caught up in encoding that I forget to save for a few pages. Inevitably my computer updates or Oxygen crashes, and all that work is lost, leading to one too many instances of my palm colliding with my forehead.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml&quot;&gt;TEI webpage&lt;/a&gt; should be considered the holy text of this class. It is referenced by Dr. Hanley, and simple guides are available on dig-eg-gaz. But if you need find anything specific, get spiritual and make a journey into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Within     s every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an “English School”. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the “Cheap Pre-paid advertisement” column on Page 5’s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the “English School, Nicosia” advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history&quot; title=&quot;Nicosia English School Official History Page&quot;&gt;notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus&quot;&gt;Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it’s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it’s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Nicosia_school.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though during this time secondary education wasn’t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Numerical Nonsense</title>
				<link>/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered many problems during the course of this class.  From
my flash drive, containing all of my microfilm scans becoming corrupted to
running out of trial time on just about every application we needed.  But the one
thing that stands above all else, is translating the minuscule blurred text,
mainly numerical values included in the financial tables.  I found the OCR
converter to be quite useless, words came out a jumbled mess and often
everything was out of order.  I ended up retyping many portions of the pages
manually, this was until I discovered stitching process and this made things a
bit easier for me.  From that point forward, I mainly just had problems
deciphering numbers and inputing them all from scratch into the templates.  The
numbers on the newspaper were very hard to make out especially the fractional
values, I could almost never distinguish what they were, and maybe if I had
scanned with more brightness or focus it would have helped but for the most
part, I think it was poor formatting of the newspaper itself.  I had to just gave
it my best guess for a majority of the pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the work was very tedious and stressful at times, definitely not for the
faint of heart.  But nothing was more rewarding than successfully accomplishing
my xml files.  Being able to read them back with ease and finally enjoy some of
the bizarre stories during this time period was very enlightening and often
very funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>XML encoding in Finereader</title>
				<link>/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Balancing a logical, accessible, and user friendly xml-encodation of the Egyptian Gazette with preserving its historical visual format is a delicate enterprise. I initially tried to do this with a plaintext editor, and later directly within the Oxygen program itself. I found myself constantly switching between windows on my computer, going back and forth and then back again between the image of the page and the xml-in-progress. By chance, I had to go and re-OCR a page three about a month into the class, and discovered something that greatly decreased the time it took me to structure a page with XML tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By placing individual text boxes over individual paragraphs on the page, Finereader would output the OCRed text in a form that was sectionally pre-divided within the plain-text-viewer. By easily distinguishing the divisions with physical space, it allowed me to rapidly go through and paste repetitive structural elements. Additionally, the image of the page (that would automatically relocate to the plain text’s location when I selected it) that was always visible aided me in determining how exactly to structure the divisions to both best maintain the paper’s original appearance and take advantage of the power of XML coding to analyze it. I then used Oxygen to functionally check and edit the code. Combined, I found that these factors greatly reduced the amount of time it took me to structurally code the text.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Silent Killer</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine reading one of the leading newspapers in the country and coming upon the local and general section. You read about current court cases, the recent parade happening downtown etc. and then you read that yet another person has died from the plague. You think about how devastating the plague has been to the country… Wait there’s a plague?
In the middle of the 1905 summer on June 16, the Egyptian Gazette reported that another person has died from the plague in a hospital in Damanhour. This report in the newspaper took up literally 2 lines and was probably over looked by the majority of readers. To me it seems that a widespread plague should receive a little more attention than that. Actually a lot more attention. What was the death toll at this point? How far had the plague spread? Are there any treatments being developed for the disease? What are the symptoms? All seem like plausible questions to be asked and reported on by the newspaper but haven’t been. They treated the plague as if it were just as common as the weather report. In only 2 other pages in my week was the plague reported, each being no longer than the report on the 16th.
This odd occurrence begs the question of why hadn’t the newspaper reported something of this magnitude more rigorously? Also it brings up the chilling question of what if the newspaper did it on purpose. What if they had an alternative motive? Regardless of alternative motive or blatant ignorance, the population was being misled regarding the matter of the plague. What else were they being misled about?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising</title>
				<link>/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 1970, Congress passed the &lt;strong&gt;Public Health Cigarette Smoking Act&lt;/strong&gt;, which prohibited the advertisement of cigarettes, and this law took effect on January 2, 1971. As a result, I have never seen a pro-cigarette advertisement a day in my life. And clearly, that reality differs from that of people who lived in Alexandria in 1905. Here, the Egyptian Gazette, on page three of this issue, is pushing the reader to check out an advertisement for the Cleopatra Cigarette Company, just in case they skimmed over it while reading page one  just moments before. In essence, not only does the “Gazette” advertise for this cigarette company on the very first page of their newspaper, but they also refer the reader back to that advertisement in a later section of the paper, and in doing so, they are essentially advertising for Cleopatra Cigarettes two times in one issue. This just goes to show how lax people’s views on cigarettes were back in 1905. This newspaper “begs” the reader to check out an advertisement for cigarettes, hoping that they’ll end up purchasing the &lt;em&gt;cancer sticks&lt;/em&gt; for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is beautifully juxtaposed with modern society’s view on cigarettes. For one, in 2016, you would never find an advertisement for cigarettes in a local newspaper. Moreover, there are a plethora of campaigns in existence today which put out ads and commercials to influence people to not smoke, or to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/cigs-1x-1.jpeg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of the many types of ads in existence today, aiming to make society aware of the side effects of smoking cigarettes. Being surrounded and exposed by so many negative advertisements like this, it makes me question what my view on cigarettes would be if I lived in 1905 Alexandria, and was exposed to positive ads for cigarettes. Not to mention, how I would feel if my local newspaper advertised cigarettes. And moreover, if my local newspaper advertised their own cigarette advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technology Troubles</title>
				<link>/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks of this semester I was completely dedicated to toiling for hours in order to receive an “A” in this class. I would stay up until midnight finishing editing text that was OCRd making sure that no detail was overlooked. I would spend hours working on this editing only to go back to it and find that all of my hard work had either disappeared or been undone and not for lack of saving. When I started working with Oxygen, I would find that a file I had just started coding the previous night could not be found when I went to open and edit it the next day. This setback has been a source of major frustration for obvious reasons. I don’t know whether this unfortunate series of events is occurring because of some delayed karma or because I have the dreaded apple computer but it has caused me to become lazy with the workload. That being said, I have prayed to the computer gods to fix my issues so I can save my grade and it seems to have worked so far. In the wake of my realization about how quickly the semester is coming to an end I have kicked back into gear and have decided to push through any and all technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Deadly Dates</title>
				<link>/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You love your family but there’s always those cousins that just annoy you so much that sometimes you just want to feed them some poisoned dates so you don’t have to deal with them anymore. Well that’s precisely what one man of Makhadoora village did to his cousins in May of 1905. This nameless man injected compressed dates with enough of a deadly poison to kill those who ate it. He then gave these deadly fruits to five of his cousins, two men and three women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three women ate the dates and “expired in great agony.” Now if you are not a psychopath, you might be confused as to why this man decided to off his cousins and especially in such a cruel and painful way. Did they inherit a large sum of money from grandma while the killer only received the nice china? Did they eat all of the stuffing at Thanksgiving when they knew it was his favorite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to the lack of information provided about a motive or even a name for the killer, the world may never know. One thing that is known however, is that this event did cause “considerable excitement” throughout the neighborhood due to the simple fact that it was a murder as opposed to an accidental date poisoning. In my opinion, this fact implies that the neighborhood in Keneh where the murders took place was not used to this violence which might mean that it was a fairly well-off neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that the motive could involve money? It could certainly be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical Issues</title>
				<link>/technical/vincent-technical-post/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During my journey in IFS2116, I have faced many issues. Some of the issues were easily fixed, some were hard to fix, and some are just plain impossible to fix. My first issue came along the first or second week of class
when I tried scanning my pages. The computers did not work and then I had to rescan the majority of my page threes.
The journey is long and tedious and very very time consuming. Another issue I faced was the bad quality of image in general. Many of my images
had missing words, blurred words, or a mixture of both. Some of the issues even had missing spots in the paper that left me clueless to what belonged in those spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another technical issue I came across was the ads. A lot of the ads had very tiny bold font that was very difficult to read
and faded as the ad continued down the page. Though there were many difficulties, I do have to say that I learned a great deal from these problems.
These technical issues has led me to believe that nothing is perfect and it is those little imperfections that make the Egyptian Gazette Newspaper so beautiful.
We all must understand that these pages have been passed on for over 50 years and nothing that old is perfect. The amazing thing is how researchers, like ourselves, go about solving these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/vincent-technical-post/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
