<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Issues with the Issue</title>
				<link>/technical/cooper-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-stuff-is-harder-than-it-looks&quot;&gt;This stuff is harder than it looks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most of the people in this class, I have came across a formidable amount of problems while trying to do basically every step of this project. When I first began scanning my images for OCR, the first two columns of each of my page threes were blurred out so I had to go back to the library to re-scan the images more times than seemed necessary. To add to the latter, the &lt;em&gt;AABBY&lt;/em&gt; software was not the best at recognizing the characters, ergo, it was a long and gruesome process to correct all of the errors. Formatting the edited text into TEI was quite difficult as well due to the fact that this is my first time working with code. Had this class been offered for more than one semester, it may have been feasible to accomplish everything listed in the syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/cooper-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Some *Cereal* Food for Thought</title>
				<link>/serial%20questions/Stefonek-Some-Serial-Food-For-Thought/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My serial discovery is that of reported military naval movements, particularly the movements of the Russian and Japanese fleets as a result of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/event/Russo-Japanese-War&quot;&gt;Russo-Japanse War&lt;/a&gt;. My goal is to use key words such as: “navy, battle, combat, fleet, ship, military, Nebogatoff, Tago and Rodjestvensky”, to find entries in the year of 1905. After finding as many entries as possible from the Egyptian Gazette, I will put together a spreadsheet that lists the report type (civilian or official), date, location and affiliation of each fleet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/The-Baltic-Fleet.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;The Baltic Fleet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, there will be additional information like the admiral(s) present with each fleet, the number, names and types of ships and any losses if a battle has occurred. Any information that is lacking in the newspaper can hopefully be supplemented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/russian-fleet-surrenders-at-port-arthur&quot;&gt;outside historical records&lt;/a&gt;. After collecting and organizing the data, I plan on using Google maps to plot the location and movements of the fleets, which will then be tagged with all of the non-locational data. That way, there will be a spiderweb across a map of the oceans linking points that can be clicked on for all available information on what happened there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20questions/Stefonek-Some-Serial-Food-For-Thought/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Dead of Alexandria</title>
				<link>/serial%20question/Dead-Alexandrians-Hank-Thompson/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My serial question is rather simple, I want to see how many deaths occurred in Alexandria during the year of 1905. I want to compare demographics, causes of deaths, location and from this compile a map, to the best of my ability to display this information. This map would be relatively simple; it would obviously be a map of the city corresponding to that time period with dots marking as many of the local deaths as I can manage. To help compare the causes of death, I have developed a system to differentiate the points, with red being for murder/manslaughter, green and black for disease, blue for drowning, and white for accidents. While this system is bare bones and might very well be refined as I proceed, it is the basic idea of categorization I wanted to convey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed while working on the paper that death was treated as more common place and matter of fact than what we are used to today, and decided it might be worth talking about and mapping. For instance, the paper reported on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/building-collapse-hank-thompson/&quot;&gt;collapse of a house and the death of all its occupants&lt;/a&gt; only once, and while I have not seen anything else about collapsing structures in Alexandria, I wondered if perhaps poor building practices might be involved. Its possible as I search through the papers I might find more collapses that claim people lives and from there might be able to hypothesize about infrastructural problems that might have been facing Alexandria.
By examining the local deaths of Alexandria, not only will I hopefully be able to build a rather interesting map, I might also be able to examine some problems that the city might have been facing below the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20question/Dead-Alexandrians-Hank-Thompson/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Difficulties with OCR</title>
				<link>/technical/black-difficulties-with-OCR/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the main goals in this class is to covert an old newspaper into a website that allows it to be easily accessed by anyone. In order to do this we must complete one very vital, and apparently very difficult step: covert pictures of microfilm into reader editable, text. This is called OCR (optical character recognition) and thankfully there are lots of programs available to us to make this process extremely simple, or so it’s thought. One of these programs is ABBYY’s FineReader, which was the one first suggested to us. This program apparently does wonders if you are using a Windows computer, but for us Mac users it only creates disappointment. Instead of converting our images into readable text, it converts them into an agglomeration of random characters that sometimes resemble words in the English language. I’ve provided a short example of one of these “conversions” done on the first few lines of one of my microfilm images. I’ve tried rescanning my images, making adjustments in FineReader, and tried a different OCR program to try and achieve better results and nothing has worked in my favor.  So, instead of making small corrections to the text as it should be, I am forced to basically retype the entire page. This process is &lt;strong&gt;extremely time-consuming&lt;/strong&gt; and I am positive that if I had an OCR program that loved my Mac computer as much as others seem to love Windows ones, I would have completed much more of my work by now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/black-difficulties-with-OCR/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>OCR OCSucks</title>
				<link>/technical/Sain-technical-reflection/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Although the whole process of learning new word processing and encoding programs was challenging, the most frustrating aspect was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/finereader/about-ocr/what-is-ocr/&quot;&gt;OCR&lt;/a&gt;. It is supposed to be a faster way to translate the newspaper pages into plain text, it turned out to take up about as much time as it would have to hand type it all. I felt as if no matter how many times I scanned the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nedcc.org/free-resources/preservation-leaflets/6.-reformatting/6.1-microfilm-and-microfiche&quot;&gt;microfilm&lt;/a&gt; images and changed the focus, brightness, contrast, or zoomed in on the page, it would not run through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abbyy.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;ABBYY&lt;/a&gt; in the way I was expecting it to. I was hoping to have to make minimal corrections after the scanned images were OCRed, but with all the pages I have done up to this point, I have had to make a minimum of two hours’ worth of corrections per page. The word processing software may read a majority of the words (I would estimate around 85%), I still spent a majority of my time in this class fixing the mistakes the OCR made. I also found the other programs in this class easier to use than ABBYY. Sometimes while editing a word, the image it received it from would disappear, I also found the ordering of the paragraphs challenging at times. Overall, the program may have saved me some time, but another OCR processor may be more efficient, from my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Sain-technical-reflection/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Wife Murder</title>
				<link>/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the twenty-fourth inst. of January,&lt;/em&gt; an incident involving a woman and her enraged husband occurred. The man killed his wife by hitting her on the head using a metal bar made of iron and fled the scene. &lt;strong&gt;The former clerk from Gabbari has yet to be discovered.&lt;/strong&gt;
The motive for committing this heinous crime is unknown. Perhaps his wife was cheating on him or maybe she cooked him a poor meal. I find it interesting that an event of this magnitude is not given a bigger article. Someone’s life has been ended and there is a possibility that others may be in danger. More information should be provided and this news story should not be shrugged off as an every day occurrence Either way, the suspect is still at large and he needs to be caught before he spreads his mayhem elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Running out of Time</title>
				<link>/technical/Taylor-blog-post-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Converting images to text has been a difficult process from start to finish. From the very start, FineReader did not seem to be responding well to my scans. It produced a multitude of errors (nearly every other word at points) that did not seem to be the result of poor scans. Then, one day I went to do some more work with it, and the program wouldn’t start up even though my trial period was not over yet. It displayed a message which said that ABBYY FineReader 12 would be terminated because it was corrupted. I discovered that one other student had the exact same problem, so at least I knew that it was not just my little computer giving up on life from working so hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I only had a couple more page threes to do at that point. So, I used my roommate’s Mac and did those. Now that I’ve moved on to other pages, I’m just typing up whatever articles appear since this doesn’t seem to take too much longer than it did to go back and correct all the text. All in all, this class has been far more difficult than I envisioned it being (especially for someone who is not great with computers), but I am not ready to give up on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Taylor-blog-post-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Time Issues</title>
				<link>/technical/hofmeister-time-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, this class is not what I expected it to be. I did not expect
to be learning how to code things or doing xml or anything that involved
technical skills. While learning the skills is not difficult, it is
difficult to find the time it takes to complete the assignments.
I try to set aside time to complete pages and to edit the text,
however I can never find enough time. For me, this is a huge issue
because I am super obsessive about my grades and I am actually
concerned about not receiving a good grade in this class. I do not face
any technical issues, just time issues. Thus far I have completed the first
three pages of everyday , the only issue in the pages that I find is not
being able to read the data for financial tables. The data is always written
very small and it tends to be smudged and &lt;strong&gt;I hate it and it gives me a headache.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/hofmeister-time-issues/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>When a Patch Won&#39;t Do!</title>
				<link>/technical/-/curiosities/cyr-WhenAPatchWontDo/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Attempting to digitize a year of the Egyptian Gazette newspaper proves difficult as students find their individual difficulties in attempting the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year to be digitized is 1905, and each student has been given a week to digitize and examine the newspaper’s contents as the task is completed. Getting the pages from the microfilm to a more reader friendly medium is a task for a patient soul!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem encountered is a large hole that the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; print newspaper had just before it was scanned. Information lost at this stage is detrimental as there are only two copies of microfilm in the country (both copies are most likely identical copies) and a trip to London to see the original remaining Egyptian Gazette copies was, unfortunately, declined by our instructor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important lesson has been learned in preserving past information when possible. Microhistorical details can be lost, when in some rare instances, one bit of information is all it takes to piece together a puzzle that has plagued historians since the time the articles have been written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is simply accepting our realities and a great lesson towards preservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-further-study&quot;&gt;For further study:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Way to Preserve Your Newspaper:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mnhs.org/preserve/conservation/reports/nytimes_preserving.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.mnhs.org/preserve/conservation/reports/nytimes_preserving.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Started with Microfilm:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archives.state.al.us/officials/microfilmbasics02.html&quot;&gt;http://www.archives.state.al.us/officials/microfilmbasics02.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Word About Microhistory:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://historynewsnetwork.org/article/23720&quot;&gt;http://historynewsnetwork.org/article/23720&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/-/curiosities/cyr-WhenAPatchWontDo/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>“Avoid Female Society”</title>
				<link>/curiosities/black-avoid-female-society/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; includes a section called &lt;strong&gt;“CALENDAR OF THE WEEK”&lt;/strong&gt; in every issue which lists the important events happening in Alexandria and its surrounding areas. This serves as a tool to keep its citizens up-to-date with what is happening in the town and advises them to go and participate in these events. Throughout the week of August 7 to August 12, 1905, the section lists plays, concerts, and other kinds of events for general entertainment. However, the issue for August 7, 1905 includes a peculiar calendar of events. For the areas of Coptic and Mohamedan, the calendar lists actions the people should take rather than events they should attend. What is even more interesting is the actions themselves. For Sunday, August 6th, it reads, “Avoid female society” and on Tuesday, August 8, it reads “Avoid eating onions and garlic”. The week gets even more interesting by following with “Drink cold water before breakfast” and “Great abundance of watermelons”. The calendar section leaves no explanation as to why these events have been posted. I am curious to know whether it was some kind of joke or if these events were meant to be taken seriously for some kind of reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/black-avoid-female-society/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
