<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>A Regatta Is a Boat Race.</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Gazette will occasionally feature a “Sport and Play.” section, usually containing scores from cricket games. For the majority of this week, though, the section featured a regatta hosted by the Khedival Yacht Club. Unlike cricket, a regatta is a series of boat races, so I initially found its placement in the newspaper odd, until reading this sub article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL2.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Yachting in Alexandria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yachting has apparently found an audience in Alexandria’s sporting community, so much so that private owners with large money influences have begun to participate in races. (That is how I understand it at least.) I figured some additional research into these races was warranted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;The Motor Boat: Devoted to All Types of Power Craft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 4, Issue 12, by Francis P. Prial pg. 43: Prial mentions the waters near Alexandria and in Egypt in general as “splendid facilities for motorboating…” and how these waters were not receiving enough attention from craft owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the central theme in this source is motorboats, not yachts, I feel the source warrants mentioning because ideal waters might be a reason for the success that yachting in Alexandria had seen, and because the author also speaks highly of the Khedival Yacht Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1908 – &lt;em&gt;Encyclopaedia of Ships and Shipping&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert B. Mason, pg. 328: A general definition of the Khedival Yacht Club: “Established 1902. Patron, H. H. the Khedive of Egypt ; Commodore, H.H. Prince Aziz Pacha Hassan…Entrance fee, £3 ; annual subscription, £2.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the mention of an entrance fee, I assume that anyone could have participated in the regattas, and that the aforementioned private owners had the money to invest in elite crafts that could win races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1907 – &lt;em&gt;Fore’n’aft&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, pg. 62: The Khedival Yacht Club is hailed as “the only important organization of its kind in Egypt… and now has two hundred and thirty members and a fleet of fifty yachts. Weekly regattas are held in fort and numerous enjoyable social functions at the handsome club house.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, here are the results of the week in question’s regatta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/KHEDIVAL3.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Regatta Results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ananke, a privately owned craft favored by the newspaper to win the race in its class, could not withstand the wind and waters that day, and had to forfeit the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Ukah-A-Regatta-Is-a-Boat-Race/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>H &amp; C Flick, Cigar Importers</title>
				<link>/curiosities/flick-H-&-C-Flick,-Cigar-Importers/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egyptian_cigarette_industry#cite_note-5&quot;&gt;Egyptian cigarette industry&lt;/a&gt; was one of the main exports in Egypt during the time period from the 1880s to the end of the World War I. Just from reading one week of issues of the Egyptian Gazette, I could tell that cigarettes were a major part of an Egyptian’s life. There was at least one advertisement for cigarettes on each page of the newspaper, but one specific advertisement in particular stood out to me the most: “H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, Cigar Importers.” Now this specific ad might not sound important to anyone else, but to me it was very interesting and got me thinking about my ancestry. I am 99.9% sure that I am not related to these Flick’s, but I wonder what it would be like to be a Flick in Egypt in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1905, Egypt imported a total of 8,078 tonnes of tobacco and a total of 8,377 tonnes in 1906 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=qs_YlWuFjooC&amp;amp;lpg=PR3&amp;amp;pg=PA59#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Relli Shechter, &lt;em&gt;Smoking, Culture and Economy in the Middle East: The Egyptian Tobacco Market 1850-2000&lt;/em&gt;, p. 59 &lt;/a&gt;). The advertisement states that H. &amp;amp; C. Flick was the largest depot of cigars in Egypt, so I can imagine that Flick’s were a very successful in 1906 due to the increase in cigar imports from 1905 to 1906.  Egyptian tobacco was usually very poorly made and didn’t taste very well, so most of the cigarettes in Egypt were not made from Egyptian tobacco (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41339516?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;EGYPTIAN CIGARETTES AND TOBACCO, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Society of Arts&lt;/em&gt; Vol. 59, No. 3034 (JANUARY 13, 1911), pp. 201-203&lt;/a&gt;). Due to Egyptian tobacco not being up to par with what most tourists and immigrants are used to, being a cigarette importer was probably a very good business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I might not actually be related to H. &amp;amp; C. Flick, I now know that it would probably be a good family business in Egypt in 1906, but it might be harder to be a cigar importer in the United States in 2017 due to all the information about how terrible cigarettes are for our health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Blog Post by ALEX CALIENDO: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&quot;&gt;The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/flick-H-&-C-Flick,-Cigar-Importers/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Job Posting</title>
				<link>/curiosity/Crespo-JobPosting/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This advertisement is found on several issues of the week of May 22nd, 1905. When looking at this ad I found it so specific and very different from what we are used to today. The way this advertisement is written it limits the possible candidates for the job. Today job postings look very different, they are very vague and do not state many details pertaining the actual job. This job posting on the other hand even states that they want male candidates who are unmarried and under 26 years of age. These specifications are put in place because they know that people with these characteristics will be fit to work the most amount of hours and dedicate most of their time to just working. It is crazy how this advertisement even emphasizes the nationality they want to hire and religious affiliation. Today employers look for some of these same qualities but they do not make it public because they could be accused of practicing discrimination in who they hire. In this time and place picking and choosing candidate based on these factors was not seen as something bad, but today this is against the law. Many different advertisements on the Egyptian Gazette are as specific as this one, therefore it seems like this is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosity/Crespo-JobPosting/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Result of hashish</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Barbosa-Hashish/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A husband bought some hashish paste, which, after some research, is a recreational drug that has the same active ingredients as marijuana. He had a dose and made the mistake of giving his wife the rest. After she kept tasting it, she saw a fire and began to scream. Her husband rushed towards her and called the police because of the huge fire they saw. When the police arrived, there was no fire and the couple thought that a small roof lamp was the huge fire. I am curious as to whether the couple got punished for taking any form of marijuana and what any other effects happened because of the event. Did friends, family, neighbors, and co-workers make fun of them for such an event? How is marijuana use seen in society back then? Also, was marijuana common or illegal back then. Were laws on drugs strict back then? Another thing I am curious about is just how much did they take to somehow imagine a fire from a lamp. Was their event used as an example against drug use? Of course this event managed to make it into the newspaper so does that mean that it became viral over the town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Barbosa-Hashish/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Reflection on the Tech</title>
				<link>/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like this second blog post is going to saturated with negatives, so I’ll try to keep mine a little brighter by starting with the fact that this initially pain-staking process has really grown on me. At first it was a total chore, slowly trouble shooting every single issue that I had with the multiple programs I had no familiarity with (Oxygen, ABBYY Finereader, and Github), wishing that my advisor would’ve warned better beforehand of such things and hoping that I would have a free weekend again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after about 3 solid weeks of working, something clicked. I started enjoying this previously arduous work. The trouble-shooting became enjoyable, as every issue came to me as an interesting puzzle rather than a pace-breaking wall. Also, the whole philosophy behind this encoding became much clearer to me, and in a way, inspired me to take special care when it came to encoding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things on the tech side that I believe led me to enjoying this process more were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Having a larger monitor to work on: I like having all the information I need to encode in view all at once, it helps me keep things in order and it just keeps things more accurate. Having a monitor that is larger than a standard 13-15-17 in laptop screen really helped me. I was able to pull up boilerplates, have oxygen open, and have a reference scanned image open all in sizes that I could view easily. This expedited the process greatly&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using a mouse: After trying to encode and OCR on my Surface and comparing it to my work on my desktop, I noticed a night and day difference in quality of pages and general frustration. The mouse allows you to have more exact control of your cursor and gives a less clunky access to your keyboard whilst moving your cursor between multiple points quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and some other technical mishaps/advice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure you take the highest quality scans of your microfilm as possible: Because I was foolish and decided to separate my scanning sessions into different days, I ended up getting two different qualities of scans. This made OCR’ing extremely frustrating as it made some pages correctable in about 20 minutes and other pages taking over an hour and a half. In short, SCAN HIGHEST DPI POSSIBLE AND MAKE SURE THE SCANNER GLASS DOES NOT HAVE EXCESSIVE SMUDGING.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always press Ctrl+S or “Save” after every page you finish in your issues: It’s been about 3 times that I’ve been so caught up in encoding that I forget to save for a few pages. Inevitably my computer updates or Oxygen crashes, and all that work is lost, leading to one too many instances of my palm colliding with my forehead.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml&quot;&gt;TEI webpage&lt;/a&gt; should be considered the holy text of this class. It is referenced by Dr. Hanley, and simple guides are available on dig-eg-gaz. But if you need find anything specific, get spiritual and make a journey into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Into-the-Rabbit-Hole-Technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Within     s every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an “English School”. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the “Cheap Pre-paid advertisement” column on Page 5’s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the “English School, Nicosia” advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history&quot; title=&quot;Nicosia English School Official History Page&quot;&gt;notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus&quot;&gt;Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it’s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it’s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/Nicosia_school.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though during this time secondary education wasn’t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Curiosity_Berlitz_Nicosia/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Numerical Nonsense</title>
				<link>/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered many problems during the course of this class.  From
my flash drive, containing all of my microfilm scans becoming corrupted to
running out of trial time on just about every application we needed.  But the one
thing that stands above all else, is translating the minuscule blurred text,
mainly numerical values included in the financial tables.  I found the OCR
converter to be quite useless, words came out a jumbled mess and often
everything was out of order.  I ended up retyping many portions of the pages
manually, this was until I discovered stitching process and this made things a
bit easier for me.  From that point forward, I mainly just had problems
deciphering numbers and inputing them all from scratch into the templates.  The
numbers on the newspaper were very hard to make out especially the fractional
values, I could almost never distinguish what they were, and maybe if I had
scanned with more brightness or focus it would have helped but for the most
part, I think it was poor formatting of the newspaper itself.  I had to just gave
it my best guess for a majority of the pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the work was very tedious and stressful at times, definitely not for the
faint of heart.  But nothing was more rewarding than successfully accomplishing
my xml files.  Being able to read them back with ease and finally enjoy some of
the bizarre stories during this time period was very enlightening and often
very funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Numerical-Nonsense/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>XML encoding in Finereader</title>
				<link>/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Balancing a logical, accessible, and user friendly xml-encodation of the Egyptian Gazette with preserving its historical visual format is a delicate enterprise. I initially tried to do this with a plaintext editor, and later directly within the Oxygen program itself. I found myself constantly switching between windows on my computer, going back and forth and then back again between the image of the page and the xml-in-progress. By chance, I had to go and re-OCR a page three about a month into the class, and discovered something that greatly decreased the time it took me to structure a page with XML tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By placing individual text boxes over individual paragraphs on the page, Finereader would output the OCRed text in a form that was sectionally pre-divided within the plain-text-viewer. By easily distinguishing the divisions with physical space, it allowed me to rapidly go through and paste repetitive structural elements. Additionally, the image of the page (that would automatically relocate to the plain text’s location when I selected it) that was always visible aided me in determining how exactly to structure the divisions to both best maintain the paper’s original appearance and take advantage of the power of XML coding to analyze it. I then used Oxygen to functionally check and edit the code. Combined, I found that these factors greatly reduced the amount of time it took me to structurally code the text.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical%20issues/Crawford-Technical-Post/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Silent Killer</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine reading one of the leading newspapers in the country and coming upon the local and general section. You read about current court cases, the recent parade happening downtown etc. and then you read that yet another person has died from the plague. You think about how devastating the plague has been to the country… Wait there’s a plague?
In the middle of the 1905 summer on June 16, the Egyptian Gazette reported that another person has died from the plague in a hospital in Damanhour. This report in the newspaper took up literally 2 lines and was probably over looked by the majority of readers. To me it seems that a widespread plague should receive a little more attention than that. Actually a lot more attention. What was the death toll at this point? How far had the plague spread? Are there any treatments being developed for the disease? What are the symptoms? All seem like plausible questions to be asked and reported on by the newspaper but haven’t been. They treated the plague as if it were just as common as the weather report. In only 2 other pages in my week was the plague reported, each being no longer than the report on the 16th.
This odd occurrence begs the question of why hadn’t the newspaper reported something of this magnitude more rigorously? Also it brings up the chilling question of what if the newspaper did it on purpose. What if they had an alternative motive? Regardless of alternative motive or blatant ignorance, the population was being misled regarding the matter of the plague. What else were they being misled about?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Evolution of Cigarette Advertising</title>
				<link>/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 1970, Congress passed the &lt;strong&gt;Public Health Cigarette Smoking Act&lt;/strong&gt;, which prohibited the advertisement of cigarettes, and this law took effect on January 2, 1971. As a result, I have never seen a pro-cigarette advertisement a day in my life. And clearly, that reality differs from that of people who lived in Alexandria in 1905. Here, the Egyptian Gazette, on page three of this issue, is pushing the reader to check out an advertisement for the Cleopatra Cigarette Company, just in case they skimmed over it while reading page one  just moments before. In essence, not only does the “Gazette” advertise for this cigarette company on the very first page of their newspaper, but they also refer the reader back to that advertisement in a later section of the paper, and in doing so, they are essentially advertising for Cleopatra Cigarettes two times in one issue. This just goes to show how lax people’s views on cigarettes were back in 1905. This newspaper “begs” the reader to check out an advertisement for cigarettes, hoping that they’ll end up purchasing the &lt;em&gt;cancer sticks&lt;/em&gt; for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is beautifully juxtaposed with modern society’s view on cigarettes. For one, in 2016, you would never find an advertisement for cigarettes in a local newspaper. Moreover, there are a plethora of campaigns in existence today which put out ads and commercials to influence people to not smoke, or to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/cigs-1x-1.jpeg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one example of the many types of ads in existence today, aiming to make society aware of the side effects of smoking cigarettes. Being surrounded and exposed by so many negative advertisements like this, it makes me question what my view on cigarettes would be if I lived in 1905 Alexandria, and was exposed to positive ads for cigarettes. Not to mention, how I would feel if my local newspaper advertised cigarettes. And moreover, if my local newspaper advertised their own cigarette advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
