<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical</title>
				<link>/technical/rymer-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A large portion of this class involves using completely new technologies and applying them to very difficult media.  While technologies such as github, OCR, and
XML weren’t terribly hard to learn, the application of them for the first time definitely led me to some technical errors that had to be sorted out.  These technical errors
included poor text recognition that left much of the text unusable, difficult to obtain XML software, and incorrect XML tagging.  The first of these errors can be attributed
to poor condition of century old documents.  While I was able to focus the microfilm reader very well, many portions of these documents had text that was copied slightly on
top of itself and occasionally with weak ink.  This led to problems such as columns being mixed together, text that didn’t go through OCR at all, and many errors overall.
Another technical error I faced was incorrect XML tagging.  After I made all the divs in a page cascade perfectly, I found out that I had tagged headers and subheaders using
the wrong tags, which was solved using find and replace and also a lot of rearranging of the XML.  Overall, I was able to understand these new technologies fairly smoothly,
and I was able to determine the cause of a few technical errors that came up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/rymer-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technology Troubles</title>
				<link>/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For the first few weeks of this semester I was completely dedicated to toiling for hours in order to receive an “A” in this class. I would stay up until midnight finishing editing text that was OCRd making sure that no detail was overlooked. I would spend hours working on this editing only to go back to it and find that all of my hard work had either disappeared or been undone and not for lack of saving. When I started working with Oxygen, I would find that a file I had just started coding the previous night could not be found when I went to open and edit it the next day. This setback has been a source of major frustration for obvious reasons. I don’t know whether this unfortunate series of events is occurring because of some delayed karma or because I have the dreaded apple computer but it has caused me to become lazy with the workload. That being said, I have prayed to the computer gods to fix my issues so I can save my grade and it seems to have worked so far. In the wake of my realization about how quickly the semester is coming to an end I have kicked back into gear and have decided to push through any and all technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technology/frederick-technology-troubles/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Deadly Dates</title>
				<link>/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You love your family but there’s always those cousins that just annoy you so much that sometimes you just want to feed them some poisoned dates so you don’t have to deal with them anymore. Well that’s precisely what one man of Makhadoora village did to his cousins in May of 1905. This nameless man injected compressed dates with enough of a deadly poison to kill those who ate it. He then gave these deadly fruits to five of his cousins, two men and three women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three women ate the dates and “expired in great agony.” Now if you are not a psychopath, you might be confused as to why this man decided to off his cousins and especially in such a cruel and painful way. Did they inherit a large sum of money from grandma while the killer only received the nice china? Did they eat all of the stuffing at Thanksgiving when they knew it was his favorite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to the lack of information provided about a motive or even a name for the killer, the world may never know. One thing that is known however, is that this event did cause “considerable excitement” throughout the neighborhood due to the simple fact that it was a murder as opposed to an accidental date poisoning. In my opinion, this fact implies that the neighborhood in Keneh where the murders took place was not used to this violence which might mean that it was a fairly well-off neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that the motive could involve money? It could certainly be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/frederick-deadly-dates/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Break</title>
				<link>/technical/Crespo-Break/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s almost the end of the semester and I am still on the second blog post, wow. At the beginning of the semester I had a big issue, my brand-new MacBook stopped working. At first they believed my trackpad and keyboard were not working because of a virus on my computer, they gave it back after deleting the virus and it went back to not working, after that I took it back and they worked on it for another week and believed they had fixed the problem, I got it back and a few days later I was still on the same page. The Apple technicians at the bookstore got to know my name very well as I had to keep going back. In the end my MacBook took about a month to get fully repaired, they ended up having to replace the whole keyboard, so obviously, I fell behind. Once I got it back I began to work deliberately on the material, although it is not difficult work, I would still find myself spending hours in front of my computer without much progress. So much correcting, so many things to fill in, plus handling four other classes at the same time, so stressful. Cisdem OCR helped me so much more than the ABBYY OCR, it could detect the print much more precisely which made the process a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/Crespo-Break/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical Issues</title>
				<link>/technical/vincent-technical-post/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;During my journey in IFS2116, I have faced many issues. Some of the issues were easily fixed, some were hard to fix, and some are just plain impossible to fix. My first issue came along the first or second week of class
when I tried scanning my pages. The computers did not work and then I had to rescan the majority of my page threes.
The journey is long and tedious and very very time consuming. Another issue I faced was the bad quality of image in general. Many of my images
had missing words, blurred words, or a mixture of both. Some of the issues even had missing spots in the paper that left me clueless to what belonged in those spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another technical issue I came across was the ads. A lot of the ads had very tiny bold font that was very difficult to read
and faded as the ad continued down the page. Though there were many difficulties, I do have to say that I learned a great deal from these problems.
These technical issues has led me to believe that nothing is perfect and it is those little imperfections that make the Egyptian Gazette Newspaper so beautiful.
We all must understand that these pages have been passed on for over 50 years and nothing that old is perfect. The amazing thing is how researchers, like ourselves, go about solving these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/vincent-technical-post/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Discussion of Converting Text</title>
				<link>/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My biggest problem with the entire process has been with the OCR process. Perhaps due to poor original scans, or perhaps due to poor images
from the source, I have had serious problems with my OCR coming out correctly. Unfortunately, I’ve had to manually type every page and it has
caused me countless headaches and more than one mental breakdown. Luckily, things got a bit smoother after finishing all my page 3’s. That being
said, I’m still working extremely hard at catching up and finishing what I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/ragland-Discussion-of-Converting-OCR/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Technical Reflection</title>
				<link>/technical/oulette-technical/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my technical reflection is primarily negative. When the class first began I found that scanning my pages and using OCR went pretty smoothly besides the fact that many of the words were not recognized. In most cases I had to retype full paragraphs for the newspaper to make sense. When the XML editor was first introduced to me I was very lost and overwhelmed. I had no idea what XML meant or how it was supposed to change the text. However, with some assistance I have become more adept at placing structural tags and finding errors in my text. TEI-tagged XML text was also a struggle for me. I did not understand exactly how to use it and I was only able to tag two historical figures. I had never heard of the website Github until taking this class and I am still a little unsure what it is exactly used for. Again, with some practice I quickly became comfortable using it to submit the work I have completed. The final challenge I have faced are blog posts, in which I have trouble converting into Markdown and using the correct format.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/technical/oulette-technical/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Exploring Expeditions</title>
				<link>/serial%20questions/Taylor-blog-post-3/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Originally, I thought that my serial question was going to focus on missing persons and examine the amount of information provided for each particular circumstance. However, as I began to try to develop a query for that topic, I had difficulty finding much data other than what I had seen in my issue. So, I began to explore new ideas. I found myself still interested in the stories concerning specific people and began to investigate random names. I eventually found that there were multiple accounts in multiple issues tracking the movement of explorers. With this, I began to wonder about the most common reasons and locations for expeditions reported in the 1905 Egyptian Gazette. I developed a simple query to find information relating to my question by searching for items containing the word “expedition.” This brought back quite a few results. My hope is that the information gathered from these results will provide some insight into the “who, what, and why” of the expeditions reported in the paper. I also hope to discover how many of these were “successful” and what determined them to be so. I anticipate some trends in location and perhaps even in the reasons for traveling. For the final analysis, I believe that a map will be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/serial%20questions/Taylor-blog-post-3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Sad Englishman</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Ragland-A-sad-englishman/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A rather unfortunate English soldier was captured by an employee of a Turkish tobacco company who sent one of his ears to the Consul at Monastir, ordering a ransom be paid for him.  Interestingly enough, this tobacco company is still around today–in a sense.  The company was the Ottoman Empire’s largest foreign investment.  It was called “Tekel” in 1825, but is actually still called “Regie” in Lebanon.  I found it interesting that the company selling Lebanese tobacco is the same company which cut off an English soldier’s ear way back in 1905.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Ragland-A-sad-englishman/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Enteric Fever</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Eugenio-entericfever/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;While reading through the Egyptian Gazette issues I was assigned, I came across an article that has to do with Enteric Fever. This article intrigued me because I was not familiar with the disease. After reading through the article it sparked my interest and I began to look up what this disease was. I found out that Enteric Fever is also known as Typhoid Fever. This illness is associated with Salmonella typhi bacteria. After reading more about it I realized that Typhoid is caused by bacteria that is similar to Salmonella. This article discusses how it is important to carry out preventative methods for this disease in the army. It then goes on to explain that the health efficiency of the Army has been increased by a lot. They talk about how they encourage men in the army to have better hygiene in hopes for better overall health. I think this is interesting because the article discusses the different types of methods they use to prevent the disease, such as boiling drinking water. It is interesting to see the medical advances for this time compared to current time. Enteric is such a big deal during this time and the prevention of the disease is so important, however as of now I had not even recognized this disease until I read further into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Eugenio-entericfever/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
